变形金刚4
绝迹重生
搞什么，达茜，你不该来的
Oh, shit. Darcy, you really shouldn't have come.
快带我去
Show me.
北极
上头坚持要我们继续运作，不能停工
Corporate was adamant. We keep running. No stopping operations.
不行，你也要过安检，不能带相机
No, no, no. You got to go through. No cameras.
他有权开枪，国际法在这里是无效的
He's got orders to kill. I don't even think international laws apply up here.
我们首先是地质学家
We are geologists first.
如果这些东西具历史意义
If this thing has any historical significance at all,
我们就得停止运作，我说了算
we are shutting down. I'm shutting us down.
他要开枪射我吗？开抢啊
Oh, he's going to shoot me? Shoot me.
别杀她
Hey, don't kill her.
真得很夸张
This is crazy stuff.
不知道是什么
Crazy shit.
你有什么看法？
Well, what do you think?
我们要改写历史了
I think history is about to change.
美国德州
"记住芝加哥事件，通报外星人活动"
"伊格研发中心"
我是个无情的女人
I'm a nasty woman
有人终于要来上班啦
Oh, look who decided to show up for work.
我总是令人心碎
I'm a heart breaker
你只能独自痛哭
Gonna make you cry
气象预报说今天不适合冲浪吗？
What, surf report no good at South Padre?
没什么浪头，车子又没油了！你懂的，凯德
The waves are flat and I got no gas. You know that, Cade.
真没礼貌
Dude. Rude.
看看这两个小妞多辣！
Look at these two june bugs. Whoo! My, my!
这次你会付我工钱吧？
Hey, you're paying me on this one, right, Cade?
拜托你告诉我会的
Please tell me I'm getting paid.
卢卡斯，你有工作可以做就要偷笑了
You know, Lucas, a lot of guys are just happy to have a job at all.
也是啦
Yeah, I suppose.
你身上有现金吗？  - 有啊
- You got any cash on you? - Yeah.
很好
All right, good.
"感谢79年来的惠顾"
我是卢卡斯法兰尼瑞
Hey, Lucas Flannery.
我们家从1928年就掌管这个地方
Place has been in the family since '28.
我祖父一辈子都投注在上面，是不是啊，祖父？
Granddaddy ran it all his life. Ain't that right, Granddaddy?
他很快就会把这里转让给我
Real soon he's going to sign it over to me.
都是现在的电影害的
The movies nowadays, that's the trouble.
不是续集就是重拍，一堆垃圾
Sequels and remakes, bunch of crap.
那一部我就很爱
I love that one. Oh.
他又聋又老  - 我听见了
He's deaf and senile. Heard that.
这些机器只是需要维修一下
Now these just need some spit and polish.
放数位和IMAX应该都没问题
I believe they're digital, possibly IMAX.
没问题才怪，我们会自己看着办
Yeah, they're not. Mister, we'll have a look around if you want to leave us to it, okay?
以前大家都会千里迢迢...
You know, folks used to come from miles around
...来这里看大咪咪的舞女
to see the dancing girls with the big cha-chas.
我真想在他的早餐里下毒
I swear to God I am one diaper change away from poisoning his oatmeal.
老伯，如果来这里能让你开心
Hey, you hang in there, buddy.
就叫他天天带你过来嘛
If coming here makes you feel young, then you tell this kid to bring you here every day.
七块钱卖我，我就闭嘴
Seven bucks, I keep talking.
成交
Sold.
你还记得这个地方吗？
Remember this place when we were kids?
高中时你带几个马子来过？
How many girls you think you brought here in high school?
只有一个
I only remember one.
接好！
Hey, heads!
你就是这样才选不上校队
That's why you didn't make the varsity team.
看我这记长传
All right. Go long.
算了
Leave it.
迫击炮弹？
Mortar shells?
你到底经历过什么事？
What the hell happened to you?
小子，这辆卡车多少钱？
Hey, snake balls. How much for the truck?
什么卡车？
Truck?
再撑两个礼拜就不用去学校了
Two more weeks, girls, till no more classes, ever.
到时一定要边晒太阳边喝个烂醉！
Almost time to get a tan and get wasted!
"伊格"
"待修物品放置处，费用随意"
"伊格机械工程"
希望是好消息
Please, please.
"申请驳回"
拿不到奖学金，太棒了
No financial aid. Great.
我知道我到家了，谢啦
Yes, I know I'm home, thank you.
入侵者注意！请远离私人土地！
Intruder alert! Back away from the premises!
声音辨识，是我！我正在报警中
- Voice recognition. It's me! - I am dialing 911.
随便你，我不管了
Go right ahead. I don't care.
我真的要报警喽
I'm still calling 911.
芝加哥之役从此改变了世界
The Battle of Chicago was an event
死亡人数超过1300人
that permanently changed our world.
市区几乎被摧毁殆尽
Over 1,300 dead. Much of the city has been destroyed.
国安部呼吁民众通报可疑的外星人活动
Homeland Security is urging everyone to report suspicious alien activity.
国会已经立法终止了所有...
A swift act of Congress put an end to all joint operations
...军方和汽车人的联合行动
between the military and the Autobots, ending the alliance.
在座各位委员都知道
As this committee knows, the Invasion of Chicago
五年前的芝加哥事件，彻底改变了我们国家的命运
was a defining day for our nation five years ago.
所有人在那一天了解到...
The day millions of people realized that
...我们不能再让外星人替我们作战
never again can we allow aliens to fight our battles for us.
联合作战行动中止之后
A handful of Autobots were given sanctuary
幸存的汽车人获得了安置
after joint-combat operations were abolished.
仅剩少数霸天虎还在四处逃窜
Fewer than a dozen Decepticons are still on the run
这都多亏了我们中情局的...
thanks to our CIA unit,
...墓风部队
"Cemetery Wind."
至于外星科技
Hurry, let's get it to my house, guys.
最终目标是由我们美国来全权掌控 我叫提摩西
As for the alien technology, our objective remains to keep it in American control. Hi. My name is Timothy. This is my crew.
我们在瓦砾堆找到了...
We found this alien ball turret in Chicago.
..这座还可以用的旋转炮塔
We just found it in the rubble and it's all working...
情资显示日本，印度和以色列...
Word has it Japan, India,
...可能分别持有一两艘太空船
the Israelis may have gotten their hands on a couple of ships.
俄罗斯已经开始积极竞标
Apparently the Russians are starting a bidding war.
有五千块美元我们就卖，它有36根炮管...
We're taking $5,000 for it. It's got 36 guns, alien shit.
新的时代已经开始
A new era has begun.
而变形金刚的时代已经结束了
And the age of the Transformers is over.
我等你好久了
Hey, I've been waiting for you.
你穿的好辣！
You're looking hot today!
是吗？你把上衣脱掉给我看看
Oh, yeah? How about you take your shirt off?
万一被你爸看到怎么办？你要去哪？
You want me to take my shirt off right now? What would your dad think of that?
真不敢相信，太夸张了
- What the hell? - Hey, where you going? I cannot believe him. I cannot believe this.
搞什么？
What the hell?
继续往前！
All the way!
卡车？爸，你该不会砸了钱在这卡车上吧？
A truck? Dad, please tell me you didn't spend our money on this.
别担心，他花的是我的钱，共150美元
Oh, no, don't worry, he didn't. He spent my money.
这会加在你的薪水里
A hundred and fifty bucks of it. As an advance on your regular paycheck.
什么薪水？  - 你很快就会拿到
- What regular paycheck? - Which you will get back.
啥时？  - 不用想，我们破产了
- When? - Never. We're broke.
我就知道
I knew it.
亲爱的，你不要在老板和员工之间挑拨离间
Sweetheart, could you please not drive a wedge
我们不是合伙人吗？
between employer and employee. Hold on. I thought we were partners.
我手头紧，钱都花在她的礼服上了
Look, I came up short, okay? I had to buy her a prom dress.
毕业舞会能没有礼服吗？
You want me to deny her a prom dress?
那你就可以不让她找舞伴？
You might as well. You denied her a prom date.
我会陪她去所以她不需要
No, I offered to take her and chaperone.
谁会想带老爸去舞会？超怪的
Nobody wants to go to the dance with their dad. It's weird.
问题不在这  - 或许这就是问题
It's not the issue. Well, maybe it should be.
别再呛我，你们知道这引擎多值钱吗？
Hey. Could you guys Just get Off my case? You know what the engine on this runs for?
我会拆零件散卖
I can break it down and strip it for parts.
亲爱的，你的裤子愈缩愈短了
And sweetheart, your shorts are shrinking by the second, okay?
拜托用冷水洗再风干
Cold water, air dry, please.
我觉得这样很性感
I think she looks hot.
你说什么？
What did you say?
性感的少女
Like a hot teenager.
加上"少女"没有比较好，谢谢
Oh, it's the "teenager" thing that makes it better. Thank you.
我不是这个意思啦
It didn't sound like what it meant.
放到电路板那边
That goes by the circuit boards.
把蔡司镜片放在那里
Put the Zeiss lenses over there.
爸，拜托别再花钱买废物
Dad, please. You can't keep spending money on junk
然后拆散它们变成更多废物
just so you can turn it into different junk.
这里没有东西是废物
We do not use the "J" word in here.
这古董放映机稀有得很
That is a Super Simplex theater projector. It's very rare.
这个"微笑领航员"不错吧？
What about the Smile Pilot?
还有"除草运动机"都是划时代的发明
Or the Exer-Mower that I invented? Simply ahead of their time.
就跟那只没路用的看门狗一样
Yeah, like the alleged Guard-Dawg.
你惹到它了
You're gonna get him upset.
凯德！
Hey, Cade! Cade!
这东西还能用吗？
This thing still work?
才怪！  - 当然，前无古人的产品
- No! - Yes. Yes, and still groundbreaking.
你尽管躺好等它送冰啤酒来
Go back there and lay on the recliner and just wait for a cold one.
老兄，别再弄坏东西
Dude, stop breaking stuff.
各式各样的催缴单
Final notice, late notice, past due.
过来，快过来
Come on, come on.
把啤酒拿过来
Bring Daddy the alcohol. Come on.
这些是什么鬼东西？
I mean, what is all this crap people send you?
CD随身听和匣式录音带
That's a Discman and that's an 8-track tape.
听音乐用的  - 从没听说过
- Music. - Never heard of it.
那个修好可以卖100，这个250
Look, I fix that, it's 100 bucks. I fix that, it's $250.
那个如果没被你摔坏可以卖20块
If I would have been able to fix that before you broke it even more, it would have been 20 bucks.
这些钱再加上奖学金就能供你上大学
This stuff is what's gonna put you through college, as long as you land one of those scholarships.
等它拿过来要多久？
What's the estimated time of arrival, usually? Average?
所以它只会把啤酒拿到附近，就这样？
Wait. So it just brings the beer near you? That's the trick?
一两个小瑕疵别在意  - 没错
- It's got a couple kinks, man. - Yeah.
爸，你不觉得有些东西根本不该被发明吗？
Dad, you think maybe some things should never be invented?
不，你那是落伍的想法
No, I don't. That's backwards thinking.
这里是很神圣的科技殿堂
This is a temple of technology. You guys are standing in a holy place.
怎么样？你们看一下这片土地
What do you think? Why don't you look at all of this?
这都可以是你们的，不错吧？
This could be yours. What about this land?
紫衣大妈又来乱了
Purple People Eater's back and she looks hungry.
很棒对不对？
Isn't this incredible?
我就知道你们会喜欢
- I knew you would like it. - Hey, you!
这房子是我的！我不会卖！
I own this house! It's not for sale!
伊格先生，你已经六个月没缴房贷
Six months late on payments, Mr. Yeager.
你还偷接电线杆的电
And I see you stealing power at the pole.
不关你的事
Hey, that's not your concern.
你们想参观一下吗？  - 当然
- Sir, do you wanna see the property? - Sure.
我来带你们逛逛
I'd be more than happy to give you a tour.
先去看我埋的其他买家
I'll show you three other buyers I got buried out back,
然后再打爆你们的头！
then I'll crack your head open like an egg!
我警告过你别再来
I told you don't come back here anymore.
我要叫我哥来扁你一顿！
I will have my brother come back and beat your ass!
我还会叫警察！我老哥你惹不起！
and I'll bring the police when I come, too! - My brother ain't no joke!
你说杰瑞？
Who, Jerry?
他肥到光是下个车就快断气了
You bring his big ass up here, he's gonna be huffing and puffing before he can squeeze out of that car!
你敢把车开上草皮你就死定了！
You back out on my grass, you're gonna be in big trouble!
叫杰瑞来找我啊
You tell Jerry to come see me.
我会请他吃胡桃派
I'll give him some pecan pie.
她竟敢撞我围篱！
She smashed through the fence?
放轻松啦，你都快气到脑肌梗塞了
Cade, relax. You're going to have an aortic infarction.
什么鬼病？  - 脑的心脏病吧
What is that? I think it's a brain heart attack.
我已经发过了
Yeah, I've had one already.
我们现在还偷电？
So we're stealing power now?
只是跟邻居借一下
No, we're borrowing it from the neighbors.
你也太扯了
Great. That's awesome.
我毕业离家后谁来照顾你？
Once I graduate and I'm gone, who's gonna take care of you?
你在照顾我？
Oh, you take care of me?
是谁教你焊接技术？
Who taught you how to solder a circuit?
是谁教你写程式？还有梳头发？
Or write a program? Or French braid your hair?
丢螺旋球？都是我教你的
Or throw a spiral? Me. That's what I do.
谁教你不用番茄酱煮饭和记帐？
Who taught you how to cook without ketchup, or balance your checkbook?
谁总是扮演成熟的大人？
Who always has to be the grownup around here?
你说的有理，但这表示我们合作无间
All right, you got a point, okay? But that means we're a great team.
我知道最近家里状况不太好
And I know it's been sucky around here lately.
但我们会没事的，要保持信念
But we're gonna be fine, sweetie. You just gotta keep believing, okay?
伟大的发明家都这样
I mean, that's what great inventors do.
我保证将来一定会发明出有用的东西
I promise you, one day, I'm gonna build something that matters.
我相信你，爸
I believe you, Dad.
你妈妈会以你为荣
You know, your mom would be very proud of you.
一切都会没事的
It's going to be okay.
散开！向右推进！
Spread out! Push right!
这里需要两个人
Roll, roll, roll, roll. Give me two. Give me two.
守好岸边，小心慢慢来
Take the beach, nice and easy.
留在原地
All right, hold what you got.
启动迷你空拍机
Release the mini-drones.
"墓风部队"
这是毒蛇，看见老鹰了，准备开火
Vipers. Eagle in sight. Cleared hot.
有热源，船首数过来第二根烟囱
Got a heat sig. Second stack. Closest to the bow.
掠夺者01，瞄准目标区域
Predator 0-1. Captured target area.
装设定点炸药
Set charges.
队长，这是枪手01
Leader, leader, this is Gunfighter 0-1.
老鹰进入室内
Eagles moving internal. Second deck.
蛙人83，蛙人83
Frogman 83, Frogman 83.
已进入最上层，已进入最上层
Breached site on rooftop. - Breached site on rooftop. - Have Echo Platoon on standby.
让直升机知道我们要出来了！
Let the halo know we're moving external!
A队往左舷推进，B队负责右舷
Alpha, take port. Bravo, take starboard.
往右
Shift right. Shift right.
攻击目标！
Cracking steel!
不要！
No!
攻击他！
Hit him, hit him, hit him!
开火
Fire.
飞弹已发射，危险勿近
Missiles out. Danger close.
他要逃走了！追上去！
He's running! Move!
他逃走了！大家追上去！
He's on the run! He's on the run!
拜托！不要！
No! Please!
别开枪
Hold your fire.
别开枪！
Hold! Hold fire!
你们没看到我受伤了吗？
Can you not see'? I've been injured.
包围他，包围他
Box him in. Box him in.
我是医官飞轮！我是你们的盟友！
Medical Officer Ratchet! I'm a friend!
我是汽车人！
I'm an Autobot!
那你为什么要逃？
Then why are you running?
擎天柱发出这个紧急讯息
Optimus sent this distress message.
呼叫所有汽车人
Calling all Autobots.
我们成为攻击目标了
We are under targeted attack.
不要再与人类有任何联系
Cease all contact with humans.
所以我们躲了起来
We're all hiding.
所有汽车人都被追杀
All Autobots are being hunted.
情况非常危险
We're all in danger.
我在芝加哥之役失去了妹妹
I lost a sister in Chicago.
我一点都不同情你
You'll get no sympathy from me.
你们人类到底有什么毛病？
What's wrong with you humans?
不！不要...
No! Please.
停火！停火！
Check fire, check fire!
由我来了结他
He's mine now.
地狱猎人...
Lock down.
汽车人，霸天虎
Autobots, Decepticons.
像小孩一样只会打架
Like little children, always fighting.
闹得整个宇宙不得安宁
Making a mess out of the universe.
还得由我来擦屁股
Then I've got to clean it up.
想活命就告诉我他藏在哪里
There is one way you survive. Tell me where he's hiding.
擎天柱在哪？
Where is Optimus Prime?
我死也不说
Never.
那你就去死吧
Never is here.
真令人印象深刻
I must say, it is remarkable,
自从你接管了中情局之后...
really astounding, the success that the CIA has had
...表现亮眼，因此总统要我来问你...
since you have taken operational control, and so the President has asked me to ask you
...也问他...
to ask him,
...愿不愿意去白宫一趟...
to invite you both over to the White House just to powwow,
跟我们报告更多...
where we get maybe some more specifics about how
...你们追杀霸天虎余党的细节
exactly you're hunting the enemy Decepticons left.
我当局长两年了，而艾汀杰先生已经任职了25年
I've had my desk for two years. Mr. Attinger has been here for 25.
他的案子我从不过问细节
He runs the projects where I don't ask for specifics.
所以才叫秘密行动
That's why they're called Black Ops.
所以我们晚上才能睡得安稳
And why we all sleep better at night.
了解，很好，可是...
Check. That is great. So, um...
可以透露一点吗？你们进行得如何？
Any dirt on that? Uh, how, uh, that's going?
成果非凡
Outstanding.
这就是我想听的，总统会很欣慰
Great. Oh, great. I was hoping to hear that. The President will be pleased.
虽然我星期一才当上幕僚长
'Cause, I'll tell you right now, I've only been Chief of Staff since Monday, um,
但我对外星人大战很清楚
but I do know that the alien war stuff, these are...
这种会议才有趣
These are the only fun meetings.
我的工作不是要娱乐总统
Look, I'm not here to entertain the President,
但你可以告诉他这场战争...
but you may tell him that the war will be over.
...就快结束了
Soon.
万一他问了我会引用你的话
"...be over..." In case he asks, I just like to have an exact quote.
"战争就快结束了"
"War will be over soon." That is great. Such good news.
真是好消息，我想总统一定会...
And, um, the President would, I know, just love...
...非常想和汽车人领袖握个手...
Really, really love to press the flesh...
或照张像...他叫至尊大人？至尊先生？
Not flesh, obviously, but just maybe get a shot with, um... Is it Lord Prime? Sir Prime?
总统可以坐空军一号来，拍完就走
We could bop on Air Force One. It'd be just a quick bop, then we just bop in and bop back.
是我就不会让他抱太大希望
I wouldn't get his hopes up on that one.
他就叫擎天柱
Okay. He's called Optimus Prime.
非法滞留的外星战斗员
Alien combatant. Here illegally.
但他们不是盟友吗？怎么回事？
But aren't they our friends? Why?
只要他们在地球上我们就不会安全
Because our world will never truly be safe till all of them are gone.
我还以为可以办一个告别仪式
Oh. Well, I would hope we could do a much more ceremonial farewell.
毕竟我们的军队曾和他们并肩作战
Especially since our military has worked so closely with them.
但你不认同  - 地球不是他们的家
- Until you. - It's not their planet.
从来都不是
Never was.
我们该夺回主导权了
Time we take it back.
对，很好
All right, come on. Come on.
太好了
Yes. Yes.
就是这样
Oh, there you go.
不，撑住呀
No, hold it.
别抖了！抖什么抖？我又不会开除你
Stop shaking! Why are you shaking? You have the job!
你忘了吃晚餐！
You forgot to eat dinner!
就是这样我才担心你
You see why I worry?
对不起，亲爱的
Look, sorry, sweetie, I...
差一点就能成功了
I almost got it working right.
我已经做完功课也温习完期末考了
So, listen, I'm done with homework and set with finals,
我想和朋友开车去兜风，可以吗？
so I was just gonna take a little drive with some friends if that was okay with you.
不能有男生，我知道，等毕业再说
No boys, I know. Graduate first.
没错
Exactly.
你知道其他人都没有这种规定
You do know no one else has this rule, right?
规定？别说得这么难听，这叫智慧
Rule? Don't make it sound harsh, okay. It's wisdom.
我不要你大半夜的出去开车
I don't think we need to be driving around in the middle of the night.
现在已经7：45，天都黑了
It's already like quarter to eight. It's almost dark.
史普德，停下来好吗？
Spud, will you stop it?
你知道我毕业典礼那天在哪里吗？
You know where I was for my graduation?
跟我这个意外的错误在一起
Yes. With me, the mistake.
是惊喜，也是我人生中最棒的事
The surprise, Tess. And the best thing that ever happened.
我们看起来不开心吗？
Do we look unhappy? Huh?
那是我人生中最美好的一天
No. It's the greatest day of my life.
你妈过世前我答应过她
I made your mother a promise before she passed.
要让我们的宝贝参加毕业典礼
Our baby's gonna be at her graduation. That's it.
高中男生啥都不懂，慢慢才会成熟
High school boys know nothing. It's only later they turn into men.
所以如果你当时年纪大一点就不会有我
So if you were older and wiser, I wouldn't exist.
我不是这个意思，我们家是不约会的
That's not what I meant.
你不约会我也不约会
You know, this is a non-dating household, okay? You don't date, I don't date. That's it.
或许你该去约会
Well, maybe you should.
泰莎，等一下
Tessa, wait.
泰莎？
Tessa'?
我知道我管的你很紧，但不这样不行
Look. I know I've been on you, okay? But I have to be.
12到17岁是青少年危险期
Twelve to seventeen is the official teenage danger window.
我必须把你保护好
It's my job to get you through it.
你不爽我也没办法
So you can be pissed off all you want.
好啦，你可以和朋友开车去兜风
And, yes, you can take a ride with your friends.
别工作到太晚
Okay. Don't work all night.
记得吃饭
And eat.
老婆，人生中最棒的事...
Best thing that ever happened, Emily.
有她是我人生中最棒的事
She's the best thing that ever happened.
你一定会引以为傲的
You'd be proud.
糟糕
Oh, no.
怎么会这样...
Unbelievable.
真不敢相信，天啊！
Unbelievable. God!
这里一定要有值钱的东西
Something in here needs to make this family some money.
老头子，就你吧
Come on, you old wreck.
是时候看看你了
Judgment Day.
他在哪？  - 不知道
Where is he? I don't know.
"查封通知"
入侵者注意！入侵者注意！
Intruder alert! Intruder alert!
废物一个
Asshole.
我正在报警中
I am dialing 911.
泰莎，我可以算是你叔叔
Tess, I'm basically your uncle.
你家就是我家
Su casa es mi casa.
而我们就要失去这个家了
And we're going to lose the casa.
爸爸！
Dad!
来了！
Coming!
你在测试雷射吗？有的话我不进去
Are you working with lasers? If so, I'm not coming in.
我从没见过这种卡车
You guys have never seen a truck like this before.
快进来，把门锁上
Get in here. Lock that door.
这门又没锁
It doesn't have a lock.
你看水箱上的洞，它被打了个大洞！
Look! Look at the hole in the radiator. Look at the size of it.
那又怎样？
Something blew a hole in it!
这不是一般的钢
Yeah, so? It's not normal steel.
引擎里的炮弹碎片把线路都扯断了
The shrapnel in the engine, it ripped all the connections apart.
看好了，这时我的天才就用上了
And watch. And this took some Cade genius.
你们一定会喜欢
You are gonna love this.
我重新将引擎通电之后...
When I hook this back to a working battery...
呼叫所有...
Calling all...
呼叫所有汽车人
Calling all Autobots.
没错，它根本就不是卡车
Oh, yeah. I don't think it's a truck at all.
这应该是变形金刚
I think we just found a Transformer.
快逃！
Evacuate!
别跑！
Wait! Guys!
你疯了吗？这种东西不能留
Dad, are you out of your mind? You need to get that thing out of here.
我整晚都在里面，很安全的
You don't have to worry. I've been in there working all night. I'm fine.
那可不是卡车，
You know what? That's not a truck, okay? You're right.
是外星杀人机器
It's an alien killing machine. Jesus.
他死透了，整组坏了了
Dude. It's DOA. It's been recalled, totaled, done.
我知道要打去哪个单位
So, listen, there's a number that you call.
你应该要通报政府，为了美国好
You're supposed to call the government. It's the American thing to do.
通报后如果证实是外星人
You're supposed to call, and if it ends up being alien,
可以得到两万五千元
then you win $25,000.
才不会有钱  - 如果能像动物频道...
You don't win money. -And if you can capture it live...
帮它装上定位器，可以获得十万块，快打电话  - 听说是这样
Like tag it like a wild wildebeest, then you get $100,000. - Dad, we're making the call. - I heard that.
我看过广告  - 才不是这样
I've seen the commercial. They don't say that. That's not a guarantee.
所以葛瑞格在骗我罗？
You think Greg would lie to me?
如果真的是变形金刚
Look, if that's a Transformer there from the Battle of Chicago,
我要知道他如何运作
I need to know how it works.
我这个发明家搞不好能逆转胜
I'm an inventor. This could be a game changer for me!
如果能把这项科技应用在发明上
If I can apply that technology to my inventions,
我们就再也不愁吃穿了
we'd never have to worry about money again.
这种话我听腻了
I've heard that before.
两万五付我的学费和房贷绰绰有余
Twenty-five grand! It pays for my college.
再说这卡车是花我的钱买来的
It pays for the house.
严格说来属于我的，不是吗？
Besides, you used my money to buy the truck, right? So technically, that's my truck. Don't you think?
你也签过研究室智慧财产权的合约
You also signed a contract regarding all research lab l.P.
啥研究室？明明就是谷仓
Research lab? It's a barn, dude.
你这样算是违反竞业条款
You signed it and now you're competing.
你的任何点子和想法都属于我
Any idea of yours is mine. Any thought you have, I own it,
所以基本上你属于我
so basically, I own you.
我不认为你可以拥有任何人
I don't think you can own someone.
就算是德州也废止很久了
That was, like, a while ago, even in Texas.
把焊枪拿过来，帮我弄一下吊臂
All right. Bring the torch over and help me with the pulley arm.
炮弹碎片毁了他的电力系统
I think the shrapnel took out its power core.
泰莎，你看
Oh, and, Tessa, you see this?
外星杀人机器会让我这么做吗？
Would an alien killing machine let me do that?
我会通报拿奖金，但先让我研究一下
Look, I'll make the call. We'll get the money. Just first let me see if I'm right.
你想躲在家里就去吧
You want to hide in the house? Go ahead. Okay.
开始吧
Let's go. Pulley arm.
真是太夸张了！
I can't believe him!
那是什么东西？看起来好像飞弹
What is that? Looks like a missile.
就是飞弹！
It is! Whoa!
爸！
Dad!
客厅里有颗飞弹！
There's a missile in the family room!
惨了
Holy...
我要杀了你！
I'll kill you!
不！不！
No! No!
有颗飞弹在...
Dad, there's a missile in...
我要杀了你们！退后！
I'll kill you! Stay back!
别开枪！
- Oh, no. Don't shoot. Don't shoot! - Call 911! Run!
叫警察！快逃啊！
别跑！
- Lucas! - Stop!
卢卡斯？别乱动，冷静下来
Lucas? Don't move, just calm down.
给我小心点，人类
Easy, human.
别动，他不会伤害我们
Stay there. He's not going to hurt us.
武器系统损坏
Weapons systems damaged.
一颗飞弹击中你的引擎
A missile hit your engine.
我们把它拿了出来
And we took it out of you.
你伤得很重
You're hurt really bad.
我只是想帮你，这里是我家
I'm just trying to help you. You're in my home now.
我是工程师，叫凯德伊格
I'm an engineer. My name is Cade Yeager.
凯德，我欠你一个恩情
Cade, I am in your debt.
我是擎天柱
My name is Optimus Prime.
我的汽车人伙伴...
My Autobots.
...有危险
They're in danger.
我现在就得离开
I need to go. I need to go now.
你这样是能走多远？
How far you think you're gonna get?
泰莎，过来，他需要帮忙
Tessa, come here. He needs our help.
你发生了什么事？
What happened to you?
人类设下陷阱突袭我
An ambush. A trap. Set by humans.
我逃走并化身成这副模样
I escaped and took this form.
但你是我们的盟友
But you're on our side.
人类为什么要伤害你？
Why would humans hurt you?
他们背后有邪恶势力
They were not alone.
我的汽车人伙伴能把我修好
- My Autobots can repair me. - Yeah.
但你无法去找他们
If you can reach 'em.
让我来吧
What about me?
我警告你，地球的艾汀杰先生
I warn you, Mr. Attinger of Earth,
同盟是一种合约，而合约...
an alliance is a contract, and contracts,
...和人类一样...
like humans,
...都会失效
expire.
在地球上我们有个说法
On this planet, we have a saying.
"敌人的敌人就是朋友"
"The enemy of my enemy is my friend."
我也有一种说法
I also have a saying.
"我才不在乎"
"I don't care."
在墨西哥市发生了什么事？
So what happened in Mexico City?
你怎么没杀他？
I thought you had him.
我击中他三次，造成致命伤害
Three direct hits. A mortal wound.
但你的人让他跑了
Then your men allowed him to escape.
你答应过要提供情报给我
You promised me human intelligence.
还是你们根本没有情报？
Or is there such a thing?
你还是没告诉我
You know, you've still never told me.
你为什么要抓他？你听命于谁？
Why do you want him? Who are you working for?
不管去到哪个星系
Every galaxy I've traveled,
你们这些低等生物都一样
all you species are the same.
觉得万物都围绕着自己运行
You all think you're the center of the universe.
无知到极点
You have no idea.
去五金行把这些东西买齐
Go to the hardware store and you get the list. The whole list.
你要修理他？他又不是电动小火车
What, you're going to try and fix him? He's not a model train set, Cade.
但他很重要
No, that's right. He's important.
谁说的？你不能把外星人藏在这里
Yeah, but important to who? You can't keep an alien locked up in your barn.
你要干嘛，跟他玩躲猫猫？
What are you gonna do, play with him?
你能冷静  - 我也想冷静
- Will you calm down? - I'm trying to,
但我被他的大炮打中了！
but I just got hit in the head with a ten-foot cannon!
他要是吃了你，你的肌肉车就归我
If he eats you, I get the GTO.
绝对不能跟任何人说，听见没？
Not a word to anybody. Do you hear me?
不能说
Not a single word. Nobody.
"中央情报局"
我们锁定了一个高价值目标
I think we have a lock on a high-value target.
特战小组已经准备出动
Special Operations group is ready.
有什么消息？
What do you got?
特战小组接到来自德州巴黎市的通报
Sir, Special Ops just got a call from Paris, Texas.
和离开墨西哥市的卡车是同一辆
Hard match on the truck seen leaving Mexico City.
好极了，马上出动
Son of a bitch. Let's go get him.
你吃了一记重击
Took a hell of a hit, you know.
飞弹差点打中你的电源
The missile just missed your power source.
这叫火种源，它提供我们生命力 也藏有我们的记忆
We call it a Spark. It contains our life force and our memories.
对我们来说就是灵魂
Yeah, we call it a soul.
叫墓风部队行动
Scramble Cemetery Wind.
大家辛苦了，没你们的事了
Thank you for your efforts, ladies and gentlemen. This room is going dark.
请由左边出口离开
The exit is on your left.
剩下的由我来
I'll take it from here.
出去吧
Okay, let's go.
墓风部队现在出发
I'm with Cemetery Wind. We're on the move.
重复，现在出发
Repeat, on the move.
凯德...
Cade.
你为什么愿意帮我？
Why are you willing to help me?
因为你愿意相信我
I guess maybe because you trust me to.
我回来了！
I'm back!
怎么这么久！
Took you long enough!
我半路去看了医生
My head hurts. I had to go to the doctor.
我头肿了一大块
I got a welt on my head
现在就像"星际争霸战"里的角色
that makes me look like a fricking Star Trek character.
废话真多
Whatever.
你们看！
Look! Look!
进入目标区域
We're on property.
毒蛇15在你们上方
Viper 15 overhead. Angels 1.
爸！
Dad!
伊格先生，我是联邦探员詹姆斯萨伏
Mr. Yeager, my name's James Savoy. I'm a federal agent.
我们在找一辆废弃卡车
My men and I are trying to track down an abandoned truck.
这一大片土地真不错，卖掉很可惜
It's a nice spread you got here. Too bad she's for sale.
谢了，但我没有要卖
Well, thanks. She's not.
你在找的是那辆卡车吗？
That the truck you mean?
不是
Afraid not.
有人通报这里有辆问题卡车
You know, Mr. Yeager, we received a call from someone concerned about this truck.
糟了
Oh, no.
不是你吗？
That wasn't you?
我唯一的问题是...
Only thing I'm concerned about is you being on my property
...你们擅自进入我的土地
without permission.
跟我们德州人作对也要讲规矩
You know, we got a rule about people messing with people from Texas.
我不知道你说的是什么卡车
And I don't know what truck you're talking about.
害死无数美国人的那种
The kind that cost American lives.
给我搜！
Search the property!
不行，你又没有搜索令
What do you mean, "Search the property"?
我的脸就是搜索令
You don't have a warrant. My face is my warrant.
你们如果找到卡车还会给我们赏金吧？
Wait. But if you guys do find a truck, we get a reward, right?
毒蛇15在A点盘旋
Viper 15 holding, point alpha.
C小队，守在原地
Charlie team, hold tight.
进行封锁
Lock it down.
开门进去  - 前有矮墙
- Open, open, open. - Short wall. Short wall.
5号前进中
Five in. Five in.
入侵者注意！请远离私人土地！
Intruder alert! Back away from the premises.
什么鬼东西？  - 白痴发明家
- What the hell is that? - Just some dumb inventor.
没有异状
Clear.
右方没有异状
Clear. Clear right.
没有异状
Clear.
留意周遭
360. 720. Heads on a swivel.
走吧，这里什么也没有
Let's go. There's nothing here.
没发现任何迹象
There's no signs. We got nothing.
长官，垃圾桶里有未爆弹
Sir, we have a live armed missile in the trash.
未爆弹？我还亲手丢的！
Live? I carried that to the trash!
你不是说它是无效弹！
You told me that was a dud, dude.
我差点被他害死
I could be dead. Right?
好，我是找到一辆卡车没错
Look. Okay, yes, I found a truck, all right.
我想拆成零件卖
I towed it back for the parts.
昨晚还在这，今天早上就不见了
I left it here last night. This morning, it's gone.
我发誓我不知道他去了哪里
When? Where? I don't know. I swear to God. That's as much as I know about him.
"他"
"Him."
他说了"他"
He said, "Him."
他知道擎天柱在哪
He knows who the son of a bitch is.
伊格先生  - 干嘛？
- Mr. Yeager. - What?
不好意思
Excuse me.
你刚刚说了"他"
You just said, "Him."
把他们抓起来
- Take them down. - What?
放开我！
Ow! Let me go!
他们什么都不知道！要问就问我！
They don't know about the truck! I know! Just let her go.
你宁愿背叛亲人也要保护外星人？
What kind of a man betrays his flesh-and-blood brethren for alien metal?
-把他带走 -滚开！
- Get this guy out of my sight. - Get off!
放开她！他们不知道卡车的事
Let her go! They don't know about the truck.
好吧！上车！各处找一找
All right! Load up! Search the perimeter!
卢卡斯，电话是不是你打的？
Lucas, you called, didn't you?
没有！我又不认识这些可怕的家伙
No! I don't know any of these scary guys.
你竟敢对女人动粗！我要给你好看！
Oh, God! You're manhandling a woman! I'll kick your ass!
放开她！
Let her go!
爸！放开我！
- Daddy! Let me go! - You're not going anywhere.
爸！
Daddy!
你不能把我带走！
No! You're not taking me anywhere!
我是美国公民
I'm an American!
别轻举妄动  - 好，我错了
- Easy, sweetheart. - Okay, okay, okay. All right. Okay. All right. I was wrong.
萨伏，利用那个女孩
Savoy. Use the girl.
天啊！
Oh, my God! Ahh!
限你十秒内说出卡车在哪里
Now, you got ten seconds. Where's the truck?
你想对我女儿开枪？  - 你逼我的
- You're gonna shoot my little girl? - If I have to.
求求你别开枪！
Please don't shoot me! Please!
我该说的都说了！他走了
Look, I don't know. I told you everything that I know! He's gone.
之前还在里面的，我发誓！
He left. He was in the barn, I swear to God!
快放她走！
- Just let her go! - Ow!
求求你
Please, please.
他本来在里面！放开她！
He was in there! Let her go!
还剩七秒
Seven seconds.
我没骗你！他本来在的！
I'm telling you the truth! He was in there!
爸！
Dad!
叫他放开我女儿！
Tell him to get away from my little girl now!
爸！
Dad!
你敢碰她我就杀了你！
You touch her and I'll kill you!
还剩两秒
You got two seconds.
我要他说实话
I need the truth.
开枪
- Please. - Shoot her.
我在这里！
Here I am!
趴下！
- Get down! - Ahh!
凯德！他们会杀你们灭口！
Cade! They're going to kill you!
快离开这里！
Get out of here!
向右推进！到房子那边！
Push right! Headed to the house!
大家快上车！
Come on. Hurry up! Get in the car!
快上车！
- Let's go! - Daddy, get in the car!
外围部队，擎天柱往你们那边去了！
Perimeter, Optimus moving your way!
怎么回事，宝贝？他们是谁？
What's happening, baby? Who are they?
他们要那辆卡车！
It's the truck. They want the truck!
你又是谁？凭什么叫她宝贝？
"Who are they"? Who are you, and who are you calling "baby"?
回答我的问题
I know you heard me.
我是她男朋友！  - 他是我男朋友！
- I'm her boyfriend! - He's my boyfriend!
你不可能是她男朋友！
What? You're not her boyfriend!
他叫尚恩，他是车手
His name's Shane and he drives, Dad.
那些车是怎样？太吓人了吧！
What kind of cars are those? They're so scary!
又有一辆追上来了！
There's another one coming up the back!
开到玉米田里甩掉他们！
You gotta try to lose them in the cornfield!
他要追上来了！
He's coming up behind us! Go!
毒蛇15即将耗尽燃油
Viper 15, running on fumes. RTB.
我们被困住了！
They've got us cornered!
小心！
Watch out, watch out, watch out!
伊格先生，我不想在这种情况下见面
Mr. Yeager, this is not how I wanted us to meet, okay?
但我叫尚恩，我...
I'm Shane, and I'm a completely...
我不想跟你说话！好好开你的车！
And I am not talking to you! Drive the car!
小心！
Watch out! Watch out!
对他们开枪示警！
Throw 'em some warning shots!
我不知道我可以开这么好
Man, I don't know how I'm driving this good.
又提升到一个新境界了
It's like, today I've gone to a whole other level.
专心开车别说话！
Road, focus! Stop talking!
尚恩，小心！
Shane, look out!
我承认这都是我的错
This may be primarily my fault, okay.
他们说会带支票过来！
They said they were gonna bring a check!
没想到是暗杀部队！
I didn't know they were gonna send a death squad!
坐稳了！
Hang on!
有人宾果了！
Hey, we got ourselves a winner! Don's got it over here.
快闪开！
Look out!
甩掉了！干得好，你这个陌生人
We lost them! Good job, stranger from the cornfields!
那些恐怖的车又来了
The scary cars are back.
开到工厂里甩掉他们！
Lose them at the factory, Shane!
你不是很会开车吗？
I thought you knew how to drive this thing! Go!
看来那笔奖金是拿不到了
I don't think we're gonna get that money. Doesn't seem like it.
凯德！
Cade!
引他们上楼！
Take 'em upstairs!
到五楼甩掉他们
We're losing them on the fifth floor.
用那一招！  - 我知道
- Do that thing, Shane! - You know it.
哪一招？
What do you mean? What thing?
我将要做的会很可怕
What we're about to do is gonna be kind of scary.
把枪拿出来射他们！
Take out your guns and shoot them!
他们开枪了！
They're shooting at us!
泰莎，帮我拉手煞车  - 你想干嘛？
- Tessa, grab my stick! Grab my stick! - What?
她的技术是最好的
She's got the best hands in the business.
准备好了吗？拉！
Ready, Tess? Pull!
不会吧！
- No! No! No! - No f-ing way!
Oh! Yeah!
Yeah!
泰莎，你别想再出家门了！
Tessa, you are so grounded!
轮圈裂开了
Shit! The rim's cracked.
擎天柱...我们快去他那里！
Optimus. Come on, move! Move!
我的脚卡住了！等一下！
My foot's stuck! Wait, Cade!
卢卡斯！  - 等我啊！
- Lucas! - Wait! Wait!
卢卡斯，小心上面！
Lucas! Lucas, above you!
快跑！
Run!
快上车！我们走！
Come on, get in, let's go!
你一定很想看看我现在的表情
I'll bet you wish you could see my face right now.
我们就这样把卢卡斯丢下？
Lucas, we just left him?
他已经死了
He's gone.
很遗憾你们失去了朋友
My deepest sympathies for the loss of your friend.
在我确定没有人跟来之前都待在这
Stay here till I'm sure we weren't followed.
我们现在都是被狙击的目标了
We are all targets now.
我们得这样躲躲藏藏？
So we're hiding out now? That's the plan?
我们要听命于一辆卡车？
We're taking orders from a truck?
不然你有更好的办法吗？
Well, you got a better idea?
离她远一点，手别那么不安分
Hey, move away from her, kid. Don't...
听见没？
Keep your hands off her. All right? No.
你被德州的小发明家搞得灰头土脸
You got your ass kicked by a garage inventor from Texas.
我会记上这一笔
That goes on your resume.
你们全都一样！
Yeah, it goes on all of yours, too!
你以为我想听你在这里发飙吗？
Do I look like I'm in the mood for any of your shit today?
华府以为我们在追杀霸天虎
Washington thinks we were chasing a Decepticon target,
不把这一家人揪出来
but our story falls apart
我们就站不住脚了
if we don't find this Yeager family first.
他如果通报警察或FBI怎么办？
Yeah, well, what if he goes to the cops or the FBI?
他们会把他交给我们
They know to hand him over.
他回不去原本的生活了
His world as he knows it is gone.
往好处想，至少你们认识了
Well, bright side, you guys met.
他是哪里人？
Where is he from?
我说过他是德州的车手  - 德州？
I told you, he's a driver from Texas. Texas?
我不知道爱尔兰是在德州
Where, Dublin, Texas? Shamrock, Texas?
他的腔调很像小矮妖
So why does he sound like a leprechaun'?
你在爱尔兰说这种话会被揍
You'd get your ass kicked in Ireland for saying that.
但这里是德州，小绿人
Well, we're not in Ireland, Lucky Charms. We're in Texas.
你说他是车手？职业的？
And so he drives? What do you mean, he drives?
对，至少他能养活自己
Like, for a living? Yeah. At least he makes a living.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我是拉力赛车手，我是车手...
Look, I race rally cars.
...她是我的领航员
One driver. One navigator. Her.
我是被认可的
By the way, I'm totally legit.
红牛已经决定要赞助我
I just got picked up by Red Bull.
顺便告诉你
And just so you know,
我所有的财产就是那辆车
my life savings was in that car back there.
我不准你们交往  - 已经是事实了
- This is not happening. - Oh, it definitely is.
你几岁？
How old are you?
Twenty.
她才17岁
She's a 17-year-old girl.
两种方式让你选
So we can work this two ways.
一是我揍你，你叫警察来抓我
One, I punch you right in the mouth and you call the police on me.
二是...
- Dad. - Or two,
...我叫警察来抓你
I just call the cops on you
因为你诱拐未成年少女
because this is illegal. She's a minor.
我们受罗密欧与茱丽叶条款的保护
We're protected by the Romeo and Juliet laws.
我们交往一阵子了
We dated for a little while.
当时我高一，他高三，所以没问题
I was a sophomore, and he was a senior. It's fine.
问题可大了
No, it's not fine.
我们未成年就已经在一起
We've got a preexisting juvenile foundational relationship.
第22.011号条例
- Statute 22.011. - What?
"罗密欧与茱丽叶"条款
Texas statute?
德州条例？还真的有？
- That a real law? - Yep.
"罗密欧与茱丽叶"是吧？
Romeo and Juliet, huh?
你们知道他们的下场吧  - 他们相爱
- You know how those two ended up? - In love.
他们死了，你父母知道这件事吗？
Dead. Do your parents know about this?
你爸让你跟17岁的女生交往吗？
Is your dad okay with you dating a 17-year-old girl?
我五岁时他就离家了
He took off when I was five,
如果我遇到他我会问问看
but if I ever bump into him, I'll ask him.
泰莎
You know, Tessa,
我一直很信任你  - 有吗？
- I trusted you. - To what?
你要我跟你一样不享乐，不冒险
Never have fun, take a risk,
当个平凡的青少年？
be a normal teenager, like you?
我是你父亲，我尽心尽力的在照顾你
I am your father, okay? And I have been busting my ass to take care of you.
所以你就把那辆卡车开回家？
Is that what you were doing when you brought home the truck?
明明通报就会没事，现在卢卡斯死了
All you had to do was report it, and now Lucas is dead.
我的人生也完了，多谢你
And my life is over. Thank you.
你把我照顾得真好
You've taken real good care of me.
求求你别开枪
Please don't shoot me!
求求你！爸！
Please! Dad!
他们真的想杀了她
They were willing to kill her.
现在也还是
Then they still are.
幕后一定有人指使，我要把他找出来
Somebody somewhere gave that order. I'm going to find some fingerprints.
求求你们！
Please!
不！
No!
我是汽车人！我是汽车人！
I'm an Autobot! I'm an Autobot!
去找些用得上的物品
Grab whatever you think we can use for supplies.
衣服什么都好，把那部电脑带着
Clothes, anything. And take that computer.
我们走
Let's go.
"石中洞屋"
真不好控制
This is not easy.
你总有拿手的事，爸爸
You know, you don't suck at everything, Dad.
搞什么...   - "帐户已被锁定"
What the...
我就知道
I knew it.
你说他是无名小卒
You told me he was no one.
那为什么...
Well,
...他会控制我们的发明
this "no one" has our tech.
"我会把你揪出来！"
呼叫所有汽车人
Calling all Autobots.
我的妈呀！
- Whoa! Oh, my God! - Oh, my God!
太神了！超夸张的！但真的有够牛
That was insane! It was awesome, but it was insane, right?
好耶！太棒了！
Oh, yeah! Hell, yeah!
他回来了！他还活着！
He's back! He's alive!
擎天柱回来了！
Optimus is here!
我们终于又有了希望
At last. There is hope after all.
太棒了
Yeah.
自由银河的领导者回来了
Mr. Leader of the Free Galaxy is back.
我就知道你会来，我从不怀疑
I knew you'd make it. I never doubted.
我们收到了你的警讯
We got your warning.
一直都在等你的消息
We've been waiting.
没错，酷毙了，汽车人再度集结
Hell, yeah. Boom time. We got the gang back together.
人类要求我们遵守他们的游戏规则
Humans have asked us to play by their rules.
但现在规则变了
Well, the rules have just changed.
人类只会在背后捅你一刀
Human beings, bunch of backstabbin' weasels.
探长，你要明辨是非
Hound, find your inner compass.
忠诚就像一朵在恐惧...
Loyalty is but a flower in the winds
...和诱惑的暴风中凋零的花
... of fear and temptation.
你在胡扯些什么？  - 我在吟俳句
What the hell are you saying? - It's a haiku.
别闹了
Cut the crap,
否则我就把手榴弹塞进你的喉咙
before I drop a grenade down your throat.
想死就来  - 我不怕了，来啊
Try it, you'll be dead. Oh, please pull it. Please do it.
这样可以省下不少时间
You know what, it'll save us so much time.
对于地球上的一切...
Well, raise your hand
...感到无福消受的请举手
if you're thoroughly disenchanted with our little pleasant Earth vacation.
这几个搭便车的人是谁？
So, who's the stowaways?
干嘛把枪对着我？
Oh, whoa, hey, what's with the gun?
住手，他们冒了生命危险救我
Stop. Hound, both of you. They've risked their lives for mine.
要知恩图报
We owe them.
其他同伴都没消息吗？
So, there's been no sign of any others?
只剩我们几个了
- Nada. - We are all that's left.
人类把我们一个个都干掉了
They're picking us off, one by one.
我们本是可悲又落魄的四金刚
We're the pathetic, dirty foursome.
加上你就五个了
And you make five.
我们以后都要像这样...
So that's our best-case scenario?
...活在汽车人的保护下吗？
Autobot witness protection?
你想走没有人会拦你，极速赛车手
Hey, Speed Racer, you're welcome to leave anytime.
我先说清楚，超级老爸
Well, for the record, Superdad,
要躲也是跟擎天柱，而不是跟你
I'm not hiding with you. I'm hiding out with that big guy.
师父，由于你生死未卜
Sensei, with your fate unknown,
大黄蜂就暂代指挥
Bumblebee has held command,
但他完全没有一个战士该有的样子 他幼稚到不行
despite his complete and total lack of anything resembling warrior discipline. He's like a child.
让你看看我的厉害  - 你只会丢脸
This child is about to kick your ass. He brings us shame.
开打了
Cage fight.
自以为聪明
Smart ass.
他们在干嘛？
What's the matter with them?
你们看不出他那无辜大眼下的矫情吗？
Am I the lone sage who sees through this puppy-dog eyes act?
不应该这样的
It's beneath you.
我一直在等他们自相残杀
Yes, I've been waiting for them all to dispatch each other,
这样我就可以高枕无忧，自己当老大
so I could take charge with no trouble at all. Just me reporting to me.
看来他们没有你不行
Well, it sure looks like you've been missed.
各位，地狱猎人正在追杀我们
Autobots, Lock down is hunting us
而人类正在助纣为虐
and humans are helping.
我们必须搞清楚原因
We need to know why.
我不知道原因，但我大概知道是谁
Well, listen, I don't know why, but I have an idea about who.
这个空拍机有汽车人被突袭的画面
This drone I stole recorded footage of an Autobot raid.
画面很片段，但看仔细了
It's in pieces, but watch what happens here.
那是铅腿
Oh, that's Lead foot.
他死得好惨
They rip him apart.
一群野蛮人
Savages.
后来这辆卡车把他载走
And later, this truck comes to haul him off.
KSI动态科技公司
KSI. Kinetic Solutions.
政府国防和航太计划的承包商
Defense, aerospace, government contracts.
这空拍机是他们发明的
They designed this drone.
所以政府追杀你们
So these government guys just hunt you down,
再把你们交给KSI？
and then pass you off to this KSI?
KSI的总部在芝加哥
The company is headquartered in Chicago.
汽车人可能都被抓到那里
That could be where they were taken.
要进去势必得大战一场
No way to get inside without a battle.
如果有人类帮忙呢？
Well, what if you had some human help?
你们现在是要搭挡吗？
- What, are you two partners now?
亲爱的，我们现在也成了目标
Sweetie, we're targets now, too.
要回到原本的生活就得查出原因
We need to know why or we'll never get our lives back.
各位...
Autobots,
...我曾发誓不杀人类
I have sworn to never kill humans.
天大的错误
Big mistake.
但一旦让我查出谁是幕后元凶
But when I find out who's behind this,
他必死无疑
he's going to die. Hooah!
芝加哥
我们正被追捕，得按新规矩来
There's a full-on manhunt out for us, so we have some new rules.
戴识别证的都不是盟友
Anyone who has got a badge is not our friend.
我们要各个击破
We're gonna divide and conquer.
你们两个去偷食物和必需品
You two in charge of stealing food and the essentials.
其他都别拿
And nothing else.
KSI芝加哥总部就像一座堡垒
Chicago KSI headquarters is like a fortress.
我会想办法混入最高军事机密区
I'm gonna find a way into their top-secret military wing.
我会找到把柄威胁他们...
Find something to blackmail this company and the government.
...和政府，再夺回我们的自由
We're gonna get our freedom back.
早上好 乔伊斯先生
Good morning, Mr. Joyce.
那是什么声音?
What was that sound?
就是那个声音
That's "the" sound.
你要求的那个
That you asked for.
我要求的是无界空灵的声音
No, I asked for boundless. Transcendent.
当人们跨进这栋建筑物的大门时
When you walk through a door in this building,
就像跨进了未来一样
it should sound like you've stepped into the future.
现在
Present.
说
Say it.
未来
Future.
过去是历史 现在已成了过去
The past is history. The present is past.
未来才是现在
The future is now.
我为什么联系不上你?
Why can't I get in touch with you?
你不明白北极的发现意味着什么吗?
Don't you realize what the Arctic find means?
记得我们小时候听的那些故事吗?
You know that story we were all told as children
几百万年前 巨大的小行星撞击了地球
about a giant asteroid that struck the Earth
造成了恐龙的灭绝?
millions of years ago and wiped out the dinosaurs?
- 记不太清了  - 故事错了
- Vaguely.  - We were wrong.
是金属造成了大灭绝
This metal caused the great extinction.
原因和原理 我还没弄清楚
How and why, I can't yet say.
但是根据碳测定 这些可以追溯到公元前6千5百万年
But carbon dating puts it at 65 million years B.C.
你让我们去挖这种矿石 比你想得更危险
This ore you've got us digging for is a lot more dangerous than you think.
我的人...
And my people...
达茜 我想你在外面工作太久了?
Darcy, I think that you've been out in the field for far too long.
我们吃午饭的时候再谈恐龙怎么样?
Why don't we discuss dinosaurs over dinner?
- 吃小牛排?  - 没门
- Ribs?  - Not a chance.
你不知道这里都出了什么大事
You have no idea what's been happening here.
技术将要发生飞跃
We're about to make the quantum leap.
一种地球上罕见的金属
A rare-earth metal.
有不稳定的分子结构
Molecularly unstable.
没有工业用途
Industrial uses, none.
然后外星人来了
And then the aliens came.
我们找到了其中的联系
And we made the connection.
他们就由这种材料做成的
It's what they're made of.
这就是圣杯
It's the Holy Grail.
我们叫它"变形素"
"Transformium." That's what we're calling it.
引人入胜  让人着迷
Focus-grouped. Catchy.
- 已经打上了我们的商标  - 是啊
- Trademarked. - Yeah.
这是继原子分裂之后 现代物理学
This is the greatest advance in modern physics
最大的飞越
since the splitting of the atom.
这是种可以设计的物质
It's programmable matter.
现在 我们绘出了它的基因图
And now, we've mapped its genome.
- 是我  - 现在 你已经绘出了它的基因图
- I.  - Now you've mapped its genome.
就能对它发出
And now we can begin to give it
命令
instructions.
这玩意儿棒极了
This is extremely good.
看着
Watch this.
我们在任意的物质间变换
We can change anything into anything.
简直是性感 你觉得呢?
Sensual, almost. Don't you think?
你喜欢音乐吗?
Do you like music?
变成小音箱
The Pill.
来点暴力的东西?
Perhaps something a little more violent?
天啊 你成功了
My God. You've done it.
在航空领域 军事领域...
In aerospace, the military...
整个机器人工业都是我们的
We will own the entire robotics industry.
所有探索都有可能
All exploration.
下入海洋 上入宇宙 无所不达
The oceans. Space. Everything.
温布利 这是什么东西?
Wembley. What is this?
你要的水母广告啊
The jellyfish commercial that you wanted.
你说它们性感而又致命 跟女人一样
You said they were erotic yet deadly, like women.
我没说过
I never said that.
- 你说过  - 我没有
- Yes, you did.  - No, I didn't.
我肯定听你说过的
I definitely heard you say it
因为当时你在说前女友的事
'cause you were talking about your ex-girlfriend,
性感 但很专横
who was sexy, but a bitch.
巡视的时候 请别吃东西
Please don't eat on the tour.
就是她吗?
Is that her?
嘿 我找来了一大包衣服裤子
Hey, I found a whole bunch of boxes of clothes.
宝贝 你可以穿条漂亮的宽松长裤了
So, sweetie, you can get some long pants, nice, loose-fitting ones,
这短裤就扔了吧 好吗? 你们带回来了什么?
and lose the short shorts, okay? What'd you guys get?
蛋白质
It's protein.
我说过 就拿生活必需品 好吗?
Look, I said the essentials, okay?
本来这种事就不简单好吗 我们差一点就被抓了
It wasn't easy. We almost got caught.
你还偷了漱口水?
You stole mouthwash?
跟你女儿亲热的时候 我喜欢闻起来好闻点
I like to be fresh when I'm making out with your daughter.
好好笑啊
That's funny.
永远也别想
Yeah, that's not happening ever.
永远?
Ever?
这就是我们军用模型机"惊破天"
This is our military prototype, Galvatron.
这我就看不懂了
I don't understand it.
这样已经第五次
This is the fifth iteration.
为什么这东西还是这个样子?
Why does he keep turning out like this?
估计就是最后转化出了问题吧
It's just some bugs in the final render.
我是根据擎天柱的样子设计惊破天的
I modeled Galvatron after Optimus Prime.
为什么他看起来还是像威震天?
Why does he keep looking like Megatron?
转化序列将近完成 请准备
Rendering sequence is almost finished. Stand by.
就是简单的编程
Simple coding.
算法而已!
Algorithms!
数学而已!
Math!
为什么我们不能按照我们想要的设计
Why can't we make what we want to make,
用我们想要的办法去造东西呢?
the way we want to make it?
为什么?
Why?
而且 这样子看上去像是契合消费者心理的产品吗?
And does that look like a consumer-friendly face to you?
胸前那个大洞又是搞什么啊?
And what about that big hole in the chest?
我觉得挺诺 我蛮喜欢的
I think it's bad-ass. I like it.
- 赞一个  - 但我讨厌这造型
- Love it.  - Well, I hate it.
哦 他来了
Oh, here he is.
光头弗兰肯斯坦博士
That bald-headed Doc Frankenstein.
这完全是不合法的 是完全不合法的试验
Ma'am, this is not legal. This is illegal experimentation.
就算外星人也不会这样对待人类!
Aliens would never do this to people!
可能会吃了你们 杀了你们 但也仅限如此
Eat you, kill you, maybe, but that's it.
但这样完全不对! 没有人会把小孩子关进盒子里
This ain't right! Nobody puts baby in a box!
这比水刑还要糟糕!
This is worse than waterboarding!
这个小家伙一直协助我们
This little gentleman has been translating for us
转译这两个大脑中的信息
all the information that comes from these two heads.
包括他们的历史 科学 所有的一切
Their history, their science, everything.
- 这是威震天吗?  - 没错
- Is that Megatron?  - Precisely.
你怎么弄到这些的?
Where did you get all this?
政府特级委托合同
Special government contract.
现在我们了解变形金刚的一切了
Now we know everything about Transformers.
长远来说 我们就能自己造了
And now at long last we can build them ourselves.
而且还能造出更好的
And we can build them better.
好的 干得漂亮 大黄蜂 这样就能进去了
Yeah, that's good, Bee. That'll get us in.
每天有几次 KSI的员工
A couple times a day, these guys are moving
会拉车进公司 进行所谓的"扫描"
in vehicle shipments into KSI for something called "scanning."
安保措施严密
Major security all over.
所以我们最可靠的办法就是从后面的秘密研究室入口进去
So our best shot at getting in is a back classified research entrance.
明早我开着大黄蜂过去
I'm gonna drive in with Bee tomorrow morning.
不好意思
Excuse me.
在我面前不准身体接触 好吗?
There's no smooching in front of me, okay?
你真死板 再说谁还用"身体接触"这种词?
You're so square. Who even says "smooching"?
我说了吧 简直不孝
I tell you, no respect.
有些时候 真不可理喻
It's just impossible sometimes.
是啊 大黄蜂之前也这样子
Yeah. I went through that with Bumblebee.
冷静 冷静点
Calm down. Calm down.
要知道 这种情况下
You know, at a time like this,
要冷静 别在乎外表 所以你能把墨镜摘掉吗?
the idea is to keep cool, not look cool, so why don't you lose the glasses?
大概一个月前
About a month ago,
有天晚上我觉得家里有点响动
middle of the night, I thought I heard noises in my house.
那是你吗?
Was that you?
什么? 拜托 不是我
What? Come on. No way.
别骗我 小鬼
Don't lie to me, kid.
你看到那边那个配枪的家伙吗?
You see that guy with the gun out there?
这里太多人拿着枪了
There's so many guys with guns.
我这就下车告诉他
Let's get out of the car and tell him
我们要闯进去的计划 诬陷你是主谋
we're about to break in and it's your idea,
反正我没关系 我老了 我已经活够了
'cause I don't care. I'm old, I've already lived long enough.
老家伙 你真的很喜欢
You have a really bad habit
在错误的时间点提起要命的话题诶
of having these conversations at the wrong time, man.
那你准备坦白从宽 还是逼我下车去?
You want to come clean or you want me to make a mess?
先生 麻烦你能过来一下吗?
Sir, can I talk to you for a second, please?
是我 是我 那次就是我
It was me, it was me, it was me, it was me.
对不起 对不起
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
去扫描的吗?
Taking it in for scanning?
好的 你们可以走了
All right. You're good to go.
你真的死定了
I'm literally gonna kill you.
三号港扫描中
Scanning in bay three.
我们利用外星人古老的科技
We took old, alien technology
来帮我们塑造更好的今天
and made it better in every way.
隆重推出"讽刺者"
Introducing Stinger.
KSI公司 我们创造世界
KSI. We make the world.
看起来很虐
That is a bad-ass robot.
看起来跟你蛮像的 大黄蜂
He kind of looks like you, Bee.
历史是过去 现在就是未来
Here is the past. And now the future.
他们想造自己的变形金刚
They're trying to build their own versions.
至少他们造的车比这辆车藕芏喟
Well, at least they're picking cooler cars than this.
你胆敢这么跟我说话?
You talk to me like that?
大黄蜂 住手!
Bee, stop!
你现在知道 自作聪明的人有什么下场了吧?
You see what happens from being a wiseass?
给我滚出去
Now get out of here.
讽刺者 灵感来源于大黄蜂
Stinger, inspired by Bumblebee,
但青出于蓝
but better in every way.
什么! 你个混...
What! Son of a...
别 别! 你要冷静
No, no! You gotta calm down.
- 他疯了!  - 住手!
- He's crazy!  - Stop!
大黄蜂! 大黄蜂 别疯了!
Bumblebee! Bee, stop going psycho!
所以我们现在没有足够的变形素做生产 你知道吗...
你们晚了 是你晚了 是你
我的小野花 你生气的时候 我真不懂你说什么
My delicate flower, I can't understand you when you're angry.
事实上 我完全不懂你在说什么
Actually, I don't really understand you at all.
我们整个工厂都准备好生产...
Our entire factory is up and running...
不好意思 嘿!
Excuse me one second. Hey!
叫你俩呢! 懒惰胚
Hey, you two! Grease monkeys.
这边什么情况?
What the hell is going on here?
这辆老古董是什么意思?
What's with this vintage crap?
我们才不扫描这种老古董
We're not scanning collector car junk.
你觉得我们这边是干什么的?
What do you think it is that we make here?
我们写诗好吗 我们是诗人
We make poetry. We're poets.
懂吗? 你替我工作的 你记过一次 一次 懂了吗?
All right? You work for me, you get one mistake. One. Understood?
- 下次不会有了  - 肯定没下次了
- It won't happen again.  - It certainly won't.
赶快把这辆烂车开出这里
So let's get this pathetic thing out of here.
你也可以滚蛋了
And you, too.
对不起 真是抱歉
So sorry. So sorry.
我们去下个地方吧
Let's move on.
看好他 我去看看有什么线索
Watch him. I'm going to see what I can find.
安静地离开这里
Quietly get out of here.
我保证 我保证 你别生气 不然我受不了
I swear. I swear. I can't bear it when you're angry.
哇哦
Whoa.
大黄蜂 你需要冷静点
Bee, you gotta calm down right now.
我很冷静 伙计
I'm perfectly calm, dude.
那需要深呼吸 或者你们类似的方法都行
You gotta breathe, or just do whatever it is that you do.
我很冷静 很冷静 我都没碰它
I'm calm. I'm calm. I'm not even touching it.
好吧 我就碰了一小下 就一小下
Okay, I'm barely touching it. I'm barely touching it.
天啊 快点变回车形!
My God. Turn back into a car right now!
别来烦我 好吗?
Get out of my face, all right?
我们的设计团队
Our design team
从大黄蜂的造型入手
started with the Bumblebee.
但实话说 这造型设计确实挺过时了
But really, this alien's design was decrepit
说实话 算古董级别了吧
and, let's face it, antique.
我了个...
What the...
- 别太在意 大黄蜂  - 样子有点老旧 有点猥琐
- Don't take it personally, Bee.  - Kind of old and ratty.
你是想说很丑吧
You mean ugly.
- 见鬼去吧!  - 不! 不准!
- Hell, no!  - No! No!
你自以为比我更好吗?
You think you're better than me!
咦哈!
Yee-hah!
你又乱动什么了?
What did you touch?
# 跟你说了 小伙子 不要乱碰 #
# I told you, homeboy. Can't touch this #
十五分钟后去我办公室
My office in 15 minutes.
这里是第七解剖室
This is dissection room seven.
惊破天 第12次解剖手术
Galvatron, render postmortem number 12.
延续32项继续头部肢解
Continued head disfigurement at event number 32.
谈判怎么样了? 好了吗?
So what about the deal? Is it done?
你拿到"种子"了吗?
Did you get the Seed?
等禁闭抓住擎天柱就能到手了
We get it when the bounty hunter gets Prime.
与此同时 还有个小问题
Meanwhile, there has been a complication.
什么?
A what?
错了 错了
No, no.
在KSI 我们不用这个词
At KSI, we don't use words like that.
一名窝藏汽车人的平民黑入了你的一个小型侦察机
A civilian harboring the Autobots has hacked into one of your mini-drones.
说明他们可能知道你参与此事了
Meaning, they may know of your involvement.
什么?
What?
刚刚情况的确有点紧张啊
That was a little bit intense.
我需要更多的变形素来制造原型机 刻不容缓
I need more Transformium, and I need it now, to build more prototypes.
你告诉你那个外星赏金猎人
You tell your alien bounty hunter
我把整个公司都赌在上面了
that I have staked my company on this deal.
而我也就把命赌上了
And I have merely staked my life.
嘿 是你过来找我商量的 记得吗?
Hey, you came to me on this, remember?
你从中情局退休
You retire from the CIA,
我公司七位数工资聘请你 你和我
you get a seven-figure piece of my company, and you and I
一起革新国家防御体系
revolutionize national defense together.
但是 艾丁格 为了我们俩好
But, Attinger, buddy, for both our sakes,
你需要尽快
you need to deliver
把"种子"给我
the Seed.
我进来了 能看到画面吗?
I'm in. Can you see my camera?
他们在融化救护车
They're melting Ratchet.
他们在肢解救护车!
They slaughtered Ratchet!
我要把他们五马分尸!
I'm gonna tear them apart!
金属
Metal.
只是金属而已 我就是这么看待他们的
Just metal. That's what I always thought of them.
其实不是这样子的
Well, they're not.
他们也是生物 跟我们一样有灵魂的生物
They're living things, with souls like ours.
之前 我跟一个还交谈过
Once, I spoke to one.
你是研究变形素的?
And you're working with Transformium?
哦 没错 我就是做这个的
Yeah, that's what I do. I am.
我负责外部的发掘工作 但是能利用的确实不太多
I'm out there digging for it. There's just not much left to find.
所以你们现在已经黔驴技穷了吗?
So that's how badly you boys need more?
无计可施到只能融化这死掉的霸天虎了
Reduced to melting evil old Decepticons down.
不对 这是个汽车人
No. That's an Autobot there.
就是和我们一起并肩作战过的
The ones who fought for us.
- 这边我已经处理好了  - 好的
- I've got this taken care of from here.  - Right.
两边分别同时进行证件扫描
Same badge code scanned at two separate gates.
马上封锁所有机密区域
I'm having the classified area locked down now.
检查那家伙
Check that guy.
嘿!
Hey!
给我站住!
Stop right there!
站住!
Stop!
Freeze!
靠墙站好
Up against the wall.
好吧
All right.
商业间谍 这可是重罪啊 伊格尔先生
Corporate espionage. That's a very serious crime, Mr. Yeager.
喔
Wow.
我要请律师
Look, I want a lawyer.
要司法部的 要我能相信的人
The Justice Department. Somebody I can trust.
我只是想保护自己的家人 懂吗?
I'm just trying to protect my family, okay?
不要和你们公司或政府有关的律师
Not from your company, from the government.
伊格尔先生
Mr. Yeager,
你觉得我是替谁工作的?
who do you think I work for?
你要保护你的家人 这精神很高尚
You're trying to protect your family, that's admirable.
而我在保护我们国家免受外星人的战乱
I'm trying to defend the nation from alien war.
我们已经承受了一次打击了
We've had a taste of what that looks like,
我们不准备再经历一次 现在...
and we are not gonna tolerate another. Now...
接下去的结果一种是 你回你的谷仓
There is a version of this conversation where you get to go back to your barn,
你女儿顺利优等成绩毕业
your daughter gets to graduate with honors,
你之前的生活可以继续下去
and life as you know it will go on.
因为你完全不明白你在趟哪趟浑水
You have no idea what you're involved with here.
是吗?
Really?
那另一种结果呢?
What's the other version of this conversation?
是派上次杀我女儿的人呢?
The one when you send in the hired help to murder my little girl?
还是你准备自己动手解决问题?
Or you gonna man up and do it yourself?
你想要哪种?
What's your preference?
这问题我只问一遍
I'm going to ask you this once.
擎天柱在哪里?
Where is Optimus Prime?
快点 我们离开这里
Come on. Let's get out of here.
转移中 地下室见
We're moving. Basement.
他们闯进来了
They're here.
出去! 全都出去!
Get out! All of you!
科学展结束了 混球们!
Science fair's over, meatbags!
- 把这实验室毁了!  - 走开 走开!
- Destroy the lab!  - Move, move, move, move!
当心! 当心!
Look out! Look out!
摧毁一切!
Destroy it all!
危险! 安全故障! 危险...
Danger! Security breach! Danger...
伙计们! 是我啊!
Guys! It's me!
把我从这鬼地方放出去!
Break me out of this Frankenstein box!
嘿!
Hey!
住手!
Stop!
这可是公司财产!
That's company property!
他们可不是你的财产!
They're not your property!
他们是我的朋友
They were my friends.
你现在不说话啦! 探长面前不敢多嘴啦?
You ain't talking so much now! You got Hound in front of you?
动手啊
Go ahead.
让我瞧瞧你们的厉害 来啊
Show us your true colors, once and for all.
下命令把 我直接碎了他
Just give me the word, I'll splatter him.
为什么你不告诉那手指痒痒的家伙 这些只是战争的牺牲品而已
Why don't you tell Itchy Fingers here that this is all the spoils of war.
金属而已
Dead metal.
创新 也是我们科学的源泉
Innovation. What we do here is science.
就算我们不用 别人也会用的
Because if we don't do it, somebody else will.
因为科技的前进不是你能阻止的!
Because you cannot stop technology!
我们不是开发科技的耗材!
We're not your technology!
让我粉碎这家伙
Let me vaporize his ass.
我已经解开了基因码 我已经拥有你们的染色链
I broke the code. I own your whole genome.
世界会了解你的所作所为的
The world will know what you're doing here.
世界? 世界只会认可我的做法
The world? The world will approve.
如今我们能制造你们了
We can make you now.
还没有醒悟吗? 我们不需要你们了
Don't you get it? We don't need you anymore.
这话太伤人了
That was cruel.
汽车人
Autobots,
结束了
we're done.
结束了? 我们不准备大开杀戒什么吗?
We're done? We're not gonna kick a little bit of ass?
我早就准备对某人下手了
I've been itching to kill something lately.
这就是我们的机会 我们必须阻止他离开
This is our chance. We have to stop him.
你必须阻止他
You have to stop him.
这东西从来没实地测试过
It's never been tested in the field.
实验室 军事基地都可以 但日常街道上从来没试过
Labs, military bases, but not on civilian streets.
之前国防部的一个合约基地
Down there a Defense Department contract
刚刚被恐怖份子袭击
was just attacked in a terrorist attack.
现在已经是中情局军事行动了
This is now a CIA military op.
你这是正当防卫 动手啊!
You're indemnified. Respond!
我们走
Let's go.
KSI芝加哥总部 请求连接最近卫星链接
KSI Chicago, closest live sat, patch it in.
刚发生了原因不明的汽车人袭击事件
Been an unprovoked Autobot attack.
惊破天准备出发
Bring up Galvatron.
惊破天变形中
Transforming Galvatron.
惊破天连线完毕
Galvatron coming online.
惊破天准备出发
Bring up Stinger.
讽刺者连线完毕
Stinger coming online.
让这些外星恐怖分子瞧瞧 什么叫做升级版
Let's show these alien terrorists what an upgrade looks like.
惊破天和讽刺者已前往
Galvatron and Stinger are moving
指定地点进行拦截
to intercept targets.
侦察机 发现五名目标 图像清晰
Reapers. Five targets in the open. Good picture.
距离拦截两公里
Two miles to intercept.
距离200米
200 meters.
交战
Engage.
变形
Transform.
哇哦
Whoa.
是我们编的程序 对吧?
We are programming this, right?
是的 大部分是
Yes. Mostly.
系统似乎出现故障
Systems seem to have malfunctioned.
瞄准五名敌人
Targeting five bogeys.
发射火箭
Engaging rockets.
Missiles away.
后面有人 大黄蜂! 加油!
Gotta haul ass, Bee! Come on!
讽刺者正在追
Stinger is in pursuit.
误射 误射! 误射 误射!
Misfire, misfire! Misfire, misfire!
系统崩溃 惊破天刚刚自主发射了四枚火箭
System failure. Galvatron just fired four rockets.
哇哦! 他们朝我们开火了!
Whoa! They're shooting at us!
- 哇哦 哇哦 哇哦!  - 当心! 你在干什么?
- Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!  - Watch out! What are you doing?
看招!
Argh!
那是什么?
What was that?
我们需要救援队支援 可能有平民丧生
We need a full medical team now. Possible civilian casualties.
我是说你误伤了很多人 我不喜欢...
I mean, you got a lot of people in the crossfire here. I don't like...
你在创造历史 为了你的国家 为了全世界
You're making history here. For your country, for the world.
人类的自由在此一举
Human freedom is at stake.
无辜的人总会死去
Innocent people die all the time.
快点 擎天柱!
Come on, Optimus!
泰莎!
Tessa!
狠狠地打 不准失败
Make him fight. Don't let him go down.
狠狠地打!
Make him fight!
快点 快点 快点
Come on, come on. Come on, come on.
泰莎!
Tessa!
泰莎 到路边去!
Tessa, run to the field!
你根本没有灵魂!
You have no soul!
所以我无所畏惧!
That is why I have no fear!
你去死吧!
You die!
救救我!
Help me!
那是什么?
What is that?
那是我的资源 把惊破天叫回来
That's my asset. Pull Galvatron back.
去吧
Do it.
我要去救她
I got to go get her.
泰莎!
Tessa!
别出去! 他会杀了你!
Don't go out there! He'll kill you!
- 她需要我的帮助!  - 她躲起来了!
- She needs my help!  - She's hidden!
擎天柱! 擎天柱 起来 快起来!
Optimus! Optimus, get up, get up!
我动不了 快离开这里
I can't. Get out of here.
擎天柱 我为你感到遗憾 你为人类效忠
I feel sorry for you, Prime. Your allegiance to these humans.
忠于事业的麻烦之处 就是事业总会背叛你
The trouble with loyalty to a cause is that the cause will always betray you.
谁派你来的?
Who sent you here?
你认为自己从哪来的?
Where do you think you came from?
你以为你是天生的吗?
You think you were born?
不 你是被造出来的
No. You were built.
你的创造者想让你回家
And your creators want you back.
我们都效忠于某人
We all work for someone.
不 不
No, no.
不要
No.
它抓住她了!
It's got her!
- 她在车里!  - 泰莎!
- She's in the car!  - Tessa!
- 不要啊!  - 泰莎!
- No!  - Tessa!
爸!
Dad!
泰莎 出来!
Tessa, get out!
出来!
Get out!
泰莎!
Tessa!
出来! 泰莎!
Get out! Tessa!
爸 救我!
Dad, help me!
- 泰莎!  - 救我 救救我! 爸! 爸!
- Tessa!  - Help me, help me! Dad! Dad!
爸!
Dad!
- 爸!  - 泰莎! 打破玻璃!
- Dad!  - Tessa! Break the glass!
- 打破玻璃出来!  - 我在试!
- Break the glass to get out!  - I'm trying!
- 泰莎 我抓不住了!  - 爸!
- Tessa, I can't hold on!  - Dad!
泰莎!
Tessa!
- 救我!  - 打破它! 打破玻璃!
- Help me!  - Just break it! Break the glass!
泰莎...
Tess...
凯德 警告汽车人!
Cade, warn the Autobots!
爸 救我! 不要丢下我!
Dad, help me! Don't leave me!
不!
No!
把那个人类丢到垃圾堆
Take that human to the trash.
秘书先生
Mr. Secretary.
我的人在路上 这是中央情报局行动
My team is on the way. This is a CIA operation.
这是我的资源
This is my asset.
叫军队解除戒备
Tell the military to stand down.
等等 我接下白宫电话
Hang on, I have the White House.
探员 你好!
Agent, hello!
天啊
My goodness.
白宫这大家都忐忑不安
Boy, is it a flurry of excitement over here at the White House.
大家都对我非常非常生气
Everybody is super, super mad. At me.
所以 我翻了下上次会议的笔记
So, I went over my notes from our last meeting,
我不确定你有提到 在密歇根大道上方
and I'm not sure when you said anything about
会出现一艘巨型外星战舰
a "giant alien warship over Michigan Avenue."
告诉总统 这不是攻击
Tell the President this is not an attack.
还记得这艘船吗 擎天柱?
Remember this ship, Prime?
为你们这些骑士 伟大的圣骑士专门打造
Built for all you Knights, you great crusaders,
来探索宇宙的
to explore the universe.
现在被我强占了 成了我的私人监狱
Well, I commandeered it. It's my personal prison now.
擎天柱?
Optimus?
欢迎回到骑士圣殿 擎天柱
Welcome back to the Knights' Temenos, Prime.
你玷污了它
You have disgraced it.
和你的叛徒朋友们待一块吧 逃兵
Join your fellow rebels, fugitive scum.
这里关的是最稀有的标本 最森严的监狱
It's for the rarest of specimens. The worst of the worst.
已经建造了好几世纪
It's taken centuries,
我都收集了所有骑士 就差你了
but I've collected all the Knights but you.
创造者们想要清理棋盘
The creators want to sweep their chessboard clean.
我不是他人的奴隶
I'm slave to no one.
物种混杂
All this species mixing with species.
破坏了宇宙平衡
It upsets the cosmic balance.
创造者们不喜欢
The creators, they don't like it.
他们建造你 是让你遵从命令
They built you to do what you were told.
怎么还不起飞?
Why hasn't it taken off yet?
加油啊 大黄蜂 它在降落 你要登上去!
Come on, Bee, it's descending. You got to get on it!
萨伏伊 任务完成
Savoy, mission accomplished.
禁闭抓到大黄蜂了 交易即将进行
Lockdown has Prime. The deal's going down now.
去侦查点拿"种子"
Picking up the Seed at the recon point.
耐斯特 泰隆 飞船看上去没问题
Nest, Talon. L.Z. appears clear.
虽然我很享受捕猎的乐趣
Much as I've enjoyed the hunt,
但我不会想念你们这可怜的星球
I won't miss your wretched planet.
我们的交易完成了 擎天柱换"种子"
Our deal is done. One Prime for one Seed.
小心拿好
Handle it with care.
我相信你们人类已经准备好了
I trust your species is ready.
不用你操心我们人类
Don't worry about our species.
永别了 地球
Farewell, Earth.
快点 快点!
Come on, come on!
大黄蜂 快点!
Bee, come on!
这是个坏主意 但我也最喜欢坏主意了
It's a bad idea. But I'm all about bad ideas.
走吧!
Let's go!
好吧 大干一场
Well, let's rock.
这太疯狂了
This is crazy.
听着 你想反悔 现在赶紧跑
Look, you wanna cut and run, you better do it now.
我会拼命一试
I'm gonna die trying.
嘿 我不是来帮你救女儿的
Hey, I'm not here to help you get your daughter.
是你来帮我救女朋友的
You're here to help me get my girlfriend.
启动黑暗物质引擎 全速前进
Engage dark-matter drives. Full power.
我们在敌人后方
We're behind enemy lines now.
禁闭的船有陷阱 眼睛放亮点
Lockdown's ship has booby traps. Eyes open.
小心他的碎骨机 砍头机 剥皮机
Beware of his bone grinders, brain blinders, flesh peelers,
染色体逆流机
chromosomal inverters,
污泥 黑洞陷门 当然还有辐射
catatonic sludge, black hole trapdoors, and, of course, radiation.
我们动作要快 要出其不意
We must be quick. We have the element of surprise.
万不得已时再使用暴力
Let's try to use violence as a last resort.
搞定它!
Get it!
我杀死你! 杀了你!
I kill you! Kill you!
我讨厌那些东西
I hate those things.
- 太变态了  - 他已经死了
- That's freaky.  - He's not alive anymore.
好了 我们看过了 他们没在这 我们走
Well, we looked. They're not here. Let's go.
什么? 嘿 没找到泰莎 我绝不离开
What? Hey, I'm not going anywhere without Tessa.
我搞不懂 这对我有什么好处?
I'm unclear. What's in it for me?
对你有什么好处?
What's in it for you?
冷静点 我们好好谈
Easy. Let's use words.
对你的好处就是我不会杀了你
What's in it for you is I don't kill you.
我们要把老大救回来 还有那个女孩 明白没?
We're getting the boss back. And the girl. Copy?
好 好啦 很有说服力 典型的男子汉气概
Okay, okay. Very persuasive. Textbook machismo.
好吧 我们要搞点破坏
Well, then. We'll need to sabotage something.
最好快点 黑暗物质引擎快要准备好起飞了
Better hurry. Because dark-matter drives are preparing to take off.
- 很好  - 我们只有十分钟时间
- Wonderful.  - I give us 10 minutes.
那是什么声音? 引擎启动?
Is that what that sound is? The engines filling up?
你是说这玩意就要...
Are you telling me that thing's gonna be...
十分钟内就要飞离这里?
This is gonna be flying out of here in 10 minutes?
十分钟?
Ten minutes?
可能是九分钟 最坏的情况是七分钟
Could be nine. Worst case, seven.
- 人类 你们去找牢房  - 我们在浪费时间 走吧
- Humans, search the cell blocks.  - We're wasting time, let's go.
- 我们去找中心核  - 走把
- We'll find the center core.  - Let's move.
我们要阻止这艘噩梦船
We're gonna stop this nightmare ship.
在这么大的船上我们根本找不到她
We're never gonna find her in this huge ship.
就像大海捞针
Like a needle in a haystack.
泰莎!
Tessa!
棒极了 太好了
Great. Great.
那可够顺利的
That was smooth.
不 真的很顺利 让所有人都知道我们在这
No, that was really smooth, letting everybody know we're here.
现在他们就会找我们了
Now they're gonna be looking for us.
十字线 最好快点 趁我们还没进入太空之前!
Better hurry, Crosshairs, before we go into space!
这里有个小枣
Here's the little jujube right here.
你好啊 妈妈
Hello, Mama.
是谁发射了锚?
Who fired the anchors?
谁在我的船上? 有个囚犯脱逃了
Who's on my ship? We have a loose prisoner.
去吧他们给我找出来
快点 我们估计还剩六分钟
Hurry up. We got like six minutes.
我们会找到她的
We'll find her.
等等
Hold up.
后退
Back up.
快 这些玩意会发现我们 赶紧躲起来
Come on, these things are gonna find us. Hurry, hide.
哇啊!
Whoa!
武器!
Weapons!
过来 帮我 快点 快点
Come here. Help me. Hurry, hurry.
把我抬起来
Help me up.
那里有些奇怪的声音
There are some weird sounds out there.
- 那是什么?  - 我不知道
- What is that?  - I don't know.
你准备好了吗?
You ready?
跑
Run.
好吧 不打一场我们是走不成了
All right, we're not going down without a fight.
他们在拐角转弯后 我们就打他们
They turn that corner, and we're gonna take them.
你准备好了吗 还是打算让我单干?
You ready or you gonna bitch out on me?
不 我会掩护你
No, I got your back.
- 准备好了吗?  - 当然
- Are you ready?  - Absolutely.
不要辜负我 准备好没?
Don't bitch out on me. Are you ready?
嗯 准备好了
Yeah. Yeah, yeah. Yeah.
好吧! 我投降! 我投降! 我投降!
Whoa, okay! I surrender! I surrender! I surrender!
我很抱歉! 实在是对不起!
I'm so sorry! I'm so, so, so sorry!
你做了什么? 你怎么弄的?
What'd you do? How'd you do that?
我不知道!
I have no idea!
你这一无是处的胆小鬼!
You no-good, chickenshit little rat!
看啊 你看到没?
Look at that. You see that?
哇!
Whoa!
你待在这里 幸运小帅哥!
You stay here, Lucky Charms!
天啊 我一定要申请这玩意的专利
Man. I am so gonna patent this shit.
咿!
Ew!
泰莎!
Tess!
爸! 救我!
Dad! Help me!
嘿!
Hey!
- 泰莎?  - 泰莎!
- Tess?  - Tess!
快点 走 走!
Come on, move, move!
泰莎!
Tessa!
肖恩 我爱你! 我爱你! 你救了我! 你救了我!
Shane, I love you! I love you! You saved me! You saved me!
我知道 我知道
I know. I know.
谢谢 太感谢了
Thank you. Thank you so much.
- 谢谢 你救了我  - 是 他救了你 没错
- Thank you. You saved me.  - Yeah, he saved you. Yeah.
没错
Yeah.
亲爱的 我想你和"我投降"先生有很多话要聊
I think you and Mr. "I Surrender" have a lot to catch up about, sweetie.
他也救了我 你真该看看他刚才干的事
He saved me, too. You should have seen him in there.
真是我们的英雄 我们现在走吧
I mean, our hero. Let's go. Now.
- 小心四周  - 我快打开了
- Eyes open.  - I almost got it.
大块头来啦! 走 走 走
Big boy coming through! Move, move, move.
哇啊!
Whoa!
这肯定是超级监狱 小心角落
This has got to be the Supermax. Watch the corners.
有很多笼子
There's a lot of cages.
没错 这里有很多奇怪的动物
Yeah. Creepy critters in here.
我不想知道大笼子里关的是什么
I don't want to know what's in the big cage.
- 这是什么?  - 探长 不要
- What's this?  - Hound, don't do it.
你看起来倒不怎么危险
Aw, you don't look very dangerous in there.
这丑得和脓疮一样
That's festering ugliness.
我被击中了! 我倒下了! 它在溶解!
I'm hit! I'm down! It's melting!
燃烧起来了!
It burns!
我想它是酸液!
I think it's acid!
白痴 只是些粘液
Nuts. It's just shizzle.
我希望这不会传染
I hope that's not contagious.
现在我要揍你了 你活着太招人烦
I got to hurt you now. You're just too disturbing to live.
接招 贱人!
Take that, bitch!
你死了
You're dead.
- 探长!  - 他还活着!
- Hound!  - He's alive!
老大 坚持住 我们来了!
Hold on, boss, we're coming!
- 擎天柱 说话!  - 在这 快点!
- Optimus, sound off!  - In here, quick!
等等 我们来救你了!
Hang on, we're coming for you!
这艘骑士船可以分离!
The arms of this Knight Ship detach!
我们可以逃离这里! 这是一艘独立的飞船! 快点!
We can break free! It's a separate ship! Hurry!
驾驶舱在哪? 右边还是左边?
Where's the cockpit? Right or left?
- 右边!  - 我马上去 老大
- Right!  - I'm on it, boss.
快点 我们没时间了
Hurry. We have no time.
老师
Sensei.
摇滚吧! 我一直都想驾驶这种东西
Let's rock! I always wanted to fly one of these things.
我到了 老大!
I'm there, boss!
嘿 伊格尔技师
Hey, Yeager Technologies,
你能发明一条出路吗?
you gonna invent us a way out of this one?
哇啊 天啊
Whoa. My God.
我才不干
I am not doing this.
- 我不干  - 不 我们只能走这里
- I am not doing that.  - Yes, we are.
不 这很好 很稳固 来吧
No, it's good. It's stable. Come on.
绝不
No way.
亲爱的 你知道我为什么在这里吗? 我是来保护你的
Sweetie, you know why I'm here? I'm here to protect you.
你已经做得很好了
You've done great at that.
现在我想让你信任我 我们走下去 来吧
I want you to trust me right now. We're getting down. Let's go.
别往下看 好吗? 迈步 看 很简单 走吧
Don't look down, okay? Step. See, it's easy. Come on.
小心 缆线开始变细了!
Careful, these cables are starting to get thinner here!
- 迈步 走 看  - 天啊!
- Step. Step. There.  - My God!
看把 别往下看! 好吗? 别往下看
See, don't look down! All right? Don't look down.
我们很快就会到那栋建筑了!
We're gonna be at the building in no time!
你还好吗 泰莎?
You okay, Tess?
继续迈步
Keep stepping.
天啊! 天啊 爸!
My God! My God, Dad!
好了 亲爱的 你要继续走 好吗?
All right, sweetie. You need to keep moving here, okay?
- 快点!  - 我做不到
- Come on!  - I can't.
我吓死了
I'm freaking out.
你现在就要走!
You need to move now!
我不走了! 我要回船上!
I'm not moving! I'm going back to the ship!
该死!
Shit!
你不能回船上 亲爱的!
You can't go back to the ship, honey!
走着瞧!
Watch me!
你还没成年 必须听我的话!
You are not 18 years old yet and you're gonna do what I say!
现在 赶紧走!
Now let's go!
我们要往这里走 好吗 不是回头
We need to go this way, okay. Not that way.
和她说 罗密欧! 快点!
Talk to her, Romeo! Now!
看在上帝的份上 过来吧
Come on, for God's sake.
别惹我
Do not start with me.
天啊 那是什么?
My God, what is that?
好了 泰莎
All right, Tessa.
别往回看
Don't look back.
不要和我说 现在我更想回头了
Well, don't say that to me. Now I want to turn around.
没什么大不了的 亲爱的
It's nothing major, sweetie.
那表示问题很严重!
Well, that means it's totally major!
我必须把枪指向你的方向
I'm gonna have to point this gun in your direction.
感觉会像是朝你的方向 但不是
It's gonna feel like it's in your direction, but I'm not.
- 你最好快点  - 你想杀我吗?
- You better hurry.  - Are you trying to kill me?
我费了九牛二虎之力才登上这艘太空飞船!
I had to bust my ass to get up here on this spaceship!
- 开枪!  - 现在趴下!
- Shoot it!  - Get down now!
泰莎 等等! 我来救你了! 泰莎!
Tessa, wait! I'm coming for you! Tessa!
- 天啊!  - 我来了!
- My God!  - I'm coming!
坚持住!
Hold on!
你是最棒的 大黄蜂! 你是最棒的
You're the best, Bee! You are the best.
你说得太对了! 永远都别忘了
You damn right! And don't ever forget it.
看到没? 看着我! 我们已经下船了 是吧?
You see that? Look at me! We're off the ship, right?
大黄蜂! 大黄蜂! 自己人!
Bumblebee! Bumblebee! Friendly!
很多敌船追来了 上船! 上来!
Enemy ships are coming in hot. Get on! Get on!
提紧你们的裤子 我要打扁你们!
Hold your knickers, I'm punching it!
他们有三艘船!
They got three ships on them!
我给它来点刺激的!
I'm giving it the juice!
快点 大黄蜂 消灭他们!
Come on, Bee, take them out!
干得漂亮 大黄蜂!
Good move, Bee!
这是给你的 混蛋们!
This one's for you, A-holes!
如果你还有什么招数 现在赶紧使出来!
If you're gonna do something, you better do it!
快点!
Come on!
我讨厌这破烂 你驾驶 我射击
I'm sick of this crap. You fly. I shoot.
嘿 你最好让我知道怎么使用这个大家伙
Hey, you better let me fire this big-ass gun
- 让船开快点!  - 哇 哦 哦!
- and make this ship go faster!  - Whoa, whoa, whoa!
听好! 速成教学 追踪弹
Listen up! Crash course. Tracer guns.
往前推是开火 往后滑是重装弹药
Punch forward to fire, slide back to reload.
什么?
What?
推 稳 滑 重复 推 稳 滑 重复
Punch, hold, slide, repeat. Punch, hold, slide, repeat.
等等 你在说什么?
Wait. What're you talking about?
- 我不知道他是什么意思  - 祝好运
- I don't know what he means.  - Good luck.
你要去哪?
Where are you going?
释放仇恨
To lay some hate.
- 说!  - 好
- Say it!  - Okay.
推 稳 滑 重复
Punch, hold, slide, repeat.
耶 我击中一架! 喔!
Yeah, I got one! Whoo!
这些外星枪太强悍了!
These alien guns kick ass!
快点 他快追上了!
Come on, he's on us!
大黄蜂 你要快点! 低头!
Bee, you gotta move! Duck!
大黄蜂 开火!
Bee, fire the gun!
哇 喔 喔 喔!
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
哇 哦 哦!
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
太疯狂了!
That was insane!
泰莎 你还好吗?
Tess, you okay?
好吧 先生?
Okay. Sir?
你最好有保险!
You better have insurance!
保险?
Insurance?
这他妈是艘宇宙飞船
It's a freaking spaceship.
你去帮一艘宇宙飞船投保试试
You go get insurance on a freaking spaceship.
祝你好运 兄弟
Good luck with that, buddy.
这是你的车?
Is this your car?
亲爱的 把外星枪给我
Sweetie, hand me my alien gun.
给你
Here you go.
过来
Come here.
- 相信你爸  - 好
- Trust your dad.  - Okay.
准备好太空发射
Prepare for interstellar launch.
我们准备好分离了 就快离开这里了
We're almost ready to separate. We're almost there.
- 快点 他要发射了!  - 好的 老大
- Hurry, he's launching!  - All over it, chief.
禁闭发现我不在时他已经在太空深处了
Lockdown will be in deep space before he realizes I'm gone.
我是很烂的飞行员 但还是试试吧
I'm a sucky pilot, but let's give it a whirl.
走吧 耶!
Hell, yeah!
你们中情局的人处事还真是巧妙
You CIA guys are really subtle.
干得漂亮 真是神不知鬼不觉
What a deft hand. I'm sure nobody noticed all that.
听着 警察肯定马上就要到了
Look. In a few minutes, there are gonna be Feds all over this place,
我可不希望他们发现圣杯
and I don't want them finding our Holy Grail.
所以带上所有设备 尽快转移到中国基地
So we're gonna take all our R&D, we're moving it to our China facility.
对
Yeah.
我想要"种子" 但我想让你把它带到那里
I want you to bring me the Seed, but I want you to bring it to me there.
约书亚先生 我认为您的产品实验存在诸多问题
Mr. Joshua, I would not describe your product testing as perfected.
我们可以在中国慢慢改进
We have plenty of time for improvements in China.
先生 惊破天 他...
Sir, Galvatron. He was...
是个失败的产品
A fiasco.
是个杂种 让我颜面尽失
A farrago. An embarrassment.
他为什么会说话?
And he spoke. How did that happen?
你知道什么叫"失误"吗 温布利?
Do you know what a flaw is, Wembley? A flaw?
"失误"就是"彻底失败"
A flaw is a total failure.
我的机器人居然不受我的控制 我很想知道是为什么!
I did not have control over my prototype, and I want to know why!
有个好消息要告诉大黄蜂 我们找到离开用的飞船了
Let's give Bumblebee the good news. We got a ship now. We're leaving.
人类 尽管我们做了这么多
You humans. After all we have done.
你们还是浑然不知自己做错了什么
You don't know what you've wrought upon yourselves.
什么情况? 你在说什么?
What? What is it now? What are you talking about?
我有点搞不清楚状况!
I mean, I'm doing stuff out of my league here!
你们看不明白是谁在控制谁
You don't see who's controlling who.
我发现的那个人造机型
Within that manmade prototype I fought,
让我觉察到
I sensed the presence
威震天的存在
of Megatron.
是挑起芝加哥战役的霸天虎吗?
What, the Decepticon that started the Chicago War?
你以为KSI公司要怎么制造那些机器人?
How do you think KSI built those bots in the first place?
他们有霸天虎的头颅
They had a whole mess of
打算要采集他的思想
dead Decepticon heads and they were downloading their minds!
我负责解剖工作
And I was in charge of autopsy duty.
没有同伴 也不给我好处
No union, no benefits, no nothing.
他们让我只身一人面对威震天
They hooked me up to Megatron,
但他的思想不像他们想的那样毫无生机
and that mind wasn't as dead as they thought.
他给他们想要的数据信息
He fed them the science and specs!
那样他们就可以给他打造一个新的身躯
All so they could build him a brand-new body.
他为那些机器人注入邪恶的基因
Then he infected it with his evil, nasty chromosomes.
他们有血红闪亮的眼睛 我能感受到
They had red, beady eyes. They got all in my lovely locks.
他们在他的关爱下长大
I can smell it right now.
而他运筹帷幄!
Total inside custom job!
KSI公司可能将他命名为"惊破天"
KSI might have named the body the snappy name of Galvatron,
但其实他是威震天的转世!
but that's just Megatron reincarnated!
你知道这么多 却没提醒他们?
You knew this and you didn't warn them?
小姑娘 面对死亡谁都会变得冷酷
Little girl, you can go to a pretty dark place when you on death row.
他一直在欺骗KSI公司
He's been playing KSI all this time,
这样他才能操控他们去找"种子"
all so that he could manipulate them into going after the Seed.
等等 种子?
Wait. The Seed?
那些一直追着我们的雇佣兵
Those nasty soldiers that were chasing us.
我看到他们上了船
I saw them board the ship,
带走了那个被称作"种子"的东西
and they took something that they called the Seed.
听我说 大约六百万年前...
Listen. Sixty million years ago, give or take an eon...
成千上万的星球都被"种子"机械化了
thousands of planets were cyber-formed with Seeds.
它把你们的有机体变成了组成我们的各种元素
They turned your organic life into our elemental metals.
创造者毁灭了你们的世界而造就了我们的世界
Our creators destroyed your world to make us.
惊破天想让这一切再次发生
And that's what Galvatron wants to happen again.
他想在最繁华的都市引爆种子 让生灵涂炭!
He wants to detonate that Seed in the biggest city and kill millions!
他想让世界知道 "我回来了"
He's gonna show the world, "Baby, I'm back."
冲击波会把城市夷为平地
The blast wave will incinerate that city into molten metal.
这让他能够建立起一直军队
He'll have enough to build a massive army
把你们人类永远消灭
and annihilate your species forever.
你们愚蠢的人类 正在自取灭亡
You dumb, greedy bastards just brought extinction to yourself.
不过反正不关我的事  我已经自由了
Not my problem, though. I'm free at last.
我没什么要担心的 我可以走了
Whole thing worked out good for me. I'm walking.
我们得在惊破天之前拿到种子
We got to get the Seed before Galvatron does.
中国 北京
种子是我们公司的救星
The Seed is going to be the salvation of our company.
我们今晚去提货
We take delivery tonight.
下个月在蒙古的荒漠 我们将它引爆
And next month, we detonate safely in the Mongolian desert.
就能有够用百年的变形素
And we'll create enough Transformium for a hundred years.
爸 我不想再偷偷摸摸 躲躲藏藏了
Dad, I'm tired of running and stealing.
有地方睡觉了
Well, a place to sleep.
嗯 又是非法闯入
Yeah. Just another break-in.
我像你们这么大的时候
You know, when I was your age,
也曾经很疯狂 喜欢汽车 喜欢姑娘
I liked to get a little wild. I liked cars, girls.
但后来有了泰莎
But then there was Tessa.
她出生了 从此我一心希望
And when she was born, all I ever wanted out of life
她能够健康快乐
was for her to be happy and healthy and safe.
我以为自己能够保护好她
Somehow I thought I'd always be enough to protect her.
但我没有
But I won't be.
我没做到
I'll never be.
我希望有人能做到
So somebody better be.
谢谢你今天能来 幸运小帅哥
Thanks for being here today, Lucky Charms.
谢谢你没开枪打我
Well, thanks for not shooting me when you had the chance.
不能那么便宜你
I'll have more.
好吧 我能看出来
Yeah, I can see that.
我们破解了加密通讯
We've intercepted the encrypted communications.
约书亚・乔伊斯正在去中国广州的工厂
Joshua Joyce is headed to his factory in Guangzhou, China.
嘿 大老板
Hey, big shot.
你的公司有麻烦了
Your company's in serious trouble.
你最好找个好律师
You better have a damn good lawyer.
是吗?
Really?
你才应该找个好律师
Well, you better have a great one 'cause
因为你马上就要成为炸掉城市的罪犯了
you're about to be responsible for the annihilation of a city.
现在 你听我说
Now, you listen to me.
你的网络被侵入了 模型被篡改了
Your tech has been hacked. Your prototypes are infected.
惊破天想要种子
And now Galvatron is after that Seed.
我知道你良心未泯 因为你和我一样 是个发明家
Look. I know you have a conscience because you're an inventor, like me.
千万不要让惊破天靠近种子
Do not let Galvatron anywhere near that Seed.
惊破天是我制造的 我能控制他
I control Galvatron. I created him.
你心知肚明
Deep down, I know you know.
是你的机器人在控制你
Your prototype's been controlling you.
这玩意把我们运到地球另一边要多久?
How fast can that thing get us halfway around the world?
很快 它可是宇宙飞船
Very. It's a spaceship.
要走的话 现在就快走
If we're traveling, now's the time.
不管付出什么代价 我只想回到以前
All I want is to have our life back. It's your call. Whatever you want.
自己走还是靠他们 哪个更安全?
Are we safer on our own, or are we safer with them?
她是一个守护者
She's a keeper.
肯定是继承她妈妈
Must take after her mom.
这话说得不假
I can't argue with that, kid.
快走! 我们去找种子
Move! We're retrieving the Seed,
就不用再管人类的破事了
but then we're done defending the humans.
不管? 你不管是什么意思?
What, done? What do you mean, you're done?
就是"完了" "回见" "拜拜"
Means "finished," "see ya," "good-bye."
抢了我的船? 你怎么能让他们得逞?
Hijacked part of my ship? How did you let this happen?
关闭黑暗物质引擎 以光速返航
Shut down dark-matter drive, reverse course at light speed,
赶紧回去!
and get us back!
擎天柱敢抢我的战利品
Prime's taken my trophy case.
我让他吃不了兜着走!
And he will feel my wrath!
KSI公司中国工厂
欢迎来到中国
Welcome to China.
隔离惊破天 告诉工程师不要激活他
Put Galvatron in containment. Tell the techs do not activate him.
没问题 先生
Absolutely, sir.
给我最高戒备
乔伊斯
Joyce.
能把这个交给你 我真是高兴
I cannot tell you how enthused I am to deliver this.
这是你最大的愿望吧
Top of your alien wish list.
归你了 或者说是归我们了
It's yours. Or rather ours.
我想看看我的报酬
I will need to see my advance.
五百万公司股票
Five million shares of the company.
我们携手 永远阻止战争
Together, we're gonna end human warfare.
我们将为美国建立起一支全自动化部队
We're about to build a fully automated U.S. Army.
设想一下我们会拯救多少美国人
Just think of all the American lives we're gonna save.
所有这些车都是最新的KSI民用机器人样板
我们什么时候能开始后续生产?
So how soon until we can start continuous production?
我想我们休息一段时间如何?
You know, why don't we take a beat on this for a minute?
最近我发现了一些数据...
I have some new data that I discovered and...
你不是要赖账吧?
You're not backing out on me here?
不 我不是赖账 只是...
No, I'm not backing out. I just...
我想要种子 我没说不想要
I want the Seed. I'm not saying I don't want the Seed.
我只是说不知道...
I'm just saying I don't know if I...
我是否现在就想要
if I want the Seed right now.
为了得到它 很多人付出了生命
Good men have died trying to get that thing for us.
为了你
For you.
我知道你付出很多才得到它
I know what you did to get that thing.
很多不法勾当
A lot of illegal, icky shit.
你也有把柄在我手上 所以你别威胁我
I can take you down, too, Mr. Black Ops. Don't you threaten me.
年轻的时候 我有个理想
I started this company when I was a boy,
想让世界变得更好 才开了这家公司
with a dream of making the world a better place.
有意思 我也有这个理想
Funny. I had the same dream.
但这么多年过去 你赚了好多钱
Somewhere along the way, you made billions of dollars.
而为什么我的理想就没实现呢?
So why don't you tell me what's missing from my dream?
为什么它就没能实现呢?
Why don't you tell me what's missing from my boyhood dream?
我最好的年华都在为祖国效力
I have served my country for decades of unparalleled prosperity
你是我最后的稻草
and you are my golden parachute.
所以你现在和我在一条船上!
So you are damn well jumping out of the plane with me!
惊破天来了!
I am Galvatron!
- 怎么回事?  - 惊破天被激活了
- What's going on?  - Your Galvatron has gone active.
你有什么事瞒着我?
What haven't you been telling me?
通知达茜 给我备车 悄悄地
Find Darcy, and bring a car around downstairs. Quietly.
工厂有紧急情况 我得走了
We got a factory emergency. I have to get you out of here.
- 发生了什么?  - 送他们出去
- What the hell's going on?  - Take them outside.
我们说好了的 你想要的已经给你了
We had a deal. You got what you wanted.
是"它"想要的
I got what "it" wanted.
兄弟们 今天你们自由了
My brothers, today I grant you your freedom.
从现在开始 你们听命于我
And from now on, you are commanded by me.
冲啊!
Rise up!
去找种子!
Go find my Seed!
在最繁华的都市引爆种子
Detonate the Seed in the largest city.
好吧 我不想听"我早就说过"
Listen, princess. I don't wanna hear, "I told you so,"
但情况的确比我想的危险
but this is much more dangerous than I think.
上车
Get in.
惊破天侵入了其它机器人
Galvatron's hacked into the others.
- 什么?  - 约书亚
- What?  - Joshua.
- 你得处理好这些!  - 快开车!
- You have to contain this!  - Drive, drive!
狗娘养的...
Son of a...
快点 快走 快走!
Come on. Let's move, let's move, let's move!
我知道在香港怎么甩掉他们
I know how to lose them in Hong Kong.
那里有驻军会帮我们的
I know a military garrison there that will help us.
威胁中情局的杀手
Threatening a professional CIA killer.
可不是我的特长 我不想再那么做了
Possibly not my finest hour. I'd like to have that one back.
杀手? 我以为他们是你朋友!
Killer? I thought they were your friends!
不是朋友 是生意伙伴 他们给了我这颗炸弹
No. Not friends. Business. They gave me this bomb.
炸弹?
Bomb?
包里有炸弹?
Is there a bomb in the bag?
是的 包里有颗炸弹
Yes, there's a bomb in the bag.
该死
Shit.
你说你不想再帮助人类了
When you said you were done fighting for humans,
这不是你的真心话 对吧?
you didn't mean that, did you?
为了弥补你们犯下的错误
How many more of my kind must be sacrificed
我们要牺牲多少同胞?
to atone for your mistakes?
人类不就是这样吗?
Well, what do you think being human means?
我们就是这样
That's what we do.
经常做错事
We make mistakes.
但有时虽然犯了错 却能创造出杰作
And sometimes out of those mistakes come the most amazing things.
比如说我修好了你
When I fixed you, it was for a reward.
我是为了钱才那么做
That was it. That was why. For money.
那是我犯的一个错误
And it was me making a mistake.
如果我没有犯错 你就活不下来了
Without it, you wouldn't be here.
所以就算你不相信我们 也请和我做一样的事情
So even if you got no faith in us, I'm asking you to do what I do.
我希望你能够看到我们身上的闪光点
I'm asking you to look at all the junk and see the treasure.
你要对我们有信心 擎天柱 要信任我们的本性
You gotta have faith, Prime, in who we can be.
香港
一分钱都没有 我很不爽
I'm seriously pissed we're not getting paid for this.
最起码我们能干掉他
Well, at least we get to kill him.
只要卫星还能找到他 就跑不了
They're not getting away if I still got him on satellite.
某些人以为自己能骗过中情局
Some genius. Thinks he can outrun the CIA.
- 约书亚?  - 怎么了?
- Joshua?  - Yes?
炸弹的威力有多大?
How lethal is that bomb?
不知道 我查查
I don't know. Let me check.
我喜欢! 太赞了
I love this! This is so good.
等一下
Hang on.
老板从香港给我发短信了
I'm getting a text from Il Duce in Hong Kong.
"告诉我种子的爆炸影响范围"
"Need to know the Seed's estimated blast range."
哦
Duh.
我来引开他们! 把那东西带到安全的地方!
I'll do the diversion! Get that thing somewhere safe!
- 嘿嘿嘿 这车多少钱啊  - 什么事啊
- 买你车啊，给你钱啊  - 买车？
杀手就要来了! 我们快走！
Killers are coming! Guys, we gotta go!
该走了...
Guys, guys...
- 闭嘴! 闭嘴!  - 好吧! 抱歉!
- Shut up! Shut up!  - All right! I'm sorry!
好吧 快买!
All right, go ahead, go ahead!
你到底卖不卖啊 不卖不卖
你有没有搞错啊你 不卖啊走啦
买了吗? 别走啊! 等一下!
Okay, good? No, don't go! Wait!
回来回来 卖啦卖啦
- 他同意了 - 衰啊你 - 好了
Okay, he's in. Okay, okay, okay.
我要涨工资! 我要涨工资
I need a raise! I want a raise.
好! 你说多少就多少!
All right, yes! I'm sure whatever you want!
快走!
Go, go, go!
不!
No!
要追上来了! 要追上来了!
Death is on our tail! Death is on our tail!
都给我让开! 快让开!
Get out of the way, all of you! Get out of the way!
我可不想这么死了
I don't want to die like this.
堵住他们
Box them in.
快点! 过来
Hurry, hurry! Come, come.
好的 我跟着你 你真厉害!
Okay, yes. I'll follow you anywhere. You're amazing!
你得到房顶去
We're going to get you to the roof.
好吧
Good, good.
进去!
Go!
温布利: 就像一颗战略导弹 哈哈哈!
哈哈哈 真逗
LOL. That's funny.
不敢相信... 这事真发生了
I can't... this is really happening.
像我这样拥有两百亿资产的任务
A man, me, who is worth over 20 billion dollars is now
现在却被中情局追杀 这是真的
being chased by CIA assassins. That's the truth.
而且机器人还要造反
And in the middle of a robot uprising.
而我正拿着一颗战略导弹
And I'm carrying what is, in essence, a tactical nuke.
最绝的是... 最绝的是我...
And the great thing is I... the great thing is that I'm...
我都没有倒时差
I'm barely feeling any jetlag.
- 别说了!  - 怎么了?
- Just stop it!  - What?
你得躲在房顶上
You need to hide on the roof of this building.
我帮你找直升机救你
I'll get you a helicopter extraction.
好吧
Okay.
我喜欢她
I like her.
她真有魅力
I find her very attractive.
他肯定就在附近
He's definitely around here.
拜托了
Come on, come on.
我找到摩托车了!
I got a bike!
仔细搜查!
Check in there!
他们就是我说的中情局杀手
These are the CIA assassins I told you about.
哇!
Whoa!
- 朋友  - 跟我们走吧
- Guys.  - Let's go.
你们好
Hello.
嘿! 好吧
Hey! Okay.
- 拿着它  - 好的
- Pick it up.  - All right. I'm gonna.
哇
Wow.
哇 谢谢 哇! 你怎么...
Wow. Wow, thank you. Wow! How did you...
警校毕业 在读工商管理硕士之前
Police training, prior to my MBA.
我好爱你
I love you.
到屋顶去
Get to the roof.
好的
All right, okay.
去给我找种子 它就在附近!
Find my Seed. It's here!
那些机器人正在找炸弹
Those prototypes are after that bomb.
不!
No!
不 不!
No, no, no, no!
飞机上的是谁?
Who the hell's aboard that?
不可能啊
Impossible.
兄弟们 是汽车人! 把他们打下来!
Brothers, it's the Autobots! Shoot them down!
约书亚!
Joshua!
嘿 光头!
Hey, Baldy!
嘿 是我! 嘿!
Hey, it's me! Hey!
带着它! 我们走
Bring it over now! Let's go.
快跑!
Hurry up, run!
- 快跑!  - 我们走! 快点!
- Hurry! Come on!  - Let's go! Move it!
快点 把它给我!
Guys! Come on. Give it to me now!
看来我们有伴了
Looks like we might have company.
被击中了! 被击中了!
We're hit! We're hit!
他们不死 我们就得死
They live, they talk, we're dead.
- 把他们全都杀了  - 明白
- Kill them all.  - Pleasure.
我数到十!
I count ten below!
我记得你说只有一个机器人被污染
I thought you said you had one prototype get infected.
看来他现在又控制了其余的五十个
Now he's got operational control of my other 50.
过来
Come on.
快爬上去!
Climb, climb!
把他们包围
Surround them.
世界末日可能是我造成的 但你竟然带了家人
I may have started the apocalypse, but you brought your family.
这可不是好家长会做的事
And that's, you know, terrible parenting.
我真想一拳把你打晕
I'm about one second away from knocking you out,
拿着炸弹离开这里
taking the bomb, and just leaving you here.
那样最好了
Please, do me a favor.
擎天柱 汽车人 你们没事吧?
Optimus, Autobots, you alive?
- 来吧!  - 来吧!
- Come on, bitch!  - Come on!
撤退! 撤退!
Evac! Evac!
我们被夹击了!
We're getting flanked!
楼下有敌人!
We got company below!
我屁股卡住了! 大黄蜂 干掉他们!
My fat ass is stuck! Bee, take the shot!
- 快进电梯!  - 好的
- Into the elevator! Get in.  - Okay.
快点
Come on.
快下去!
Get down, get down!
把门关上! 把门关上!
Close the door! Close the door!
动不了! 门关不上!
Won't go! It's not closing!
超重了
There's too much weight.
- 你们去找大黄蜂!  - 别出去 爸!
- Get back down to Bumblebee!  - Dad, no!
嘿! 你要找的是我!
Hey! You want me!
中央电梯
Center elevator.
他不会有事的
He's gonna be okay.
有炸弹! 有炸弹! 都让开!
Alien bomb! Alien bomb, coming through!
都让开! 都... 嗨 小朋友
Clear the way! Clear the... hi, kids.
让一让 女士们!
Coming through, ladies!
借过! 借过 女士们!
Excuse me! Excuse me, ladies! Excuse me!
天啊!
My God!
"都给我让开"用中文怎么说?
How do you say, "Get the fuck out of the way" in Chinese?
这里可是很高啊
That's a long way down.
没有搞错吧
You've got to be kidding me.
不!
No!
拜托
Come on.
哇哦!
Whoa!
我来抓你了!
I'm coming for you!
你不该把卡车藏起来
Never should have hidden that truck.
你不该追杀我家人
You should have never came after my family.
真倒霉 伊格尔 我们都有家人
Tough luck, Yeager. We all have family.
对 但我能活着见到我的
Yeah, but I'm gonna live to see mine.
我那些逃走的犯人在哪儿?
Where is my escaped bounty?
汽车人在这里
Autobots at this location.
擎天柱也快来了
Prime is close.
做你该做的
Do whatever you have to do.
我知道
I intend to.
- 达茜!  - 约书亚!
- Darcy!  - Joshua!
那边还有三个过来了
We got three more coming in from that way!
大黄蜂 泰莎在哪?
Bee, where's Tessa?
爸爸!
Dad!
我们遇到难题了 知道吗? 我制造出了无与伦比的机器人
We got a real dilemma here. Okay? I created incredible robots.
都是为了打败这些变形金刚的
It's all designed to kick that fat Transformer's ass.
所以 真的 我们输定了
So, really, this is a no-win situation.
结束了
It's over.
这话太伤人
That was mean.
嘿! 我很抱歉 但这是事实嘛!
Hey! I'm sorry if you can't handle the cold-hearted truth!
擎天柱 我该拿这些人类怎么办?
Optimus, what are my orders with these humans?
我能压扁这个光头吗?
Can I squish the bald guy?
他们遇到麻烦了
They're in trouble.
管他呢! 这不是我们的战争!
Nah! This isn't our fight!
我受够做丧家犬了 真是太气人了!
I'm done being an underdog. Underdogs suck!
要我说就该教训教训他们
I say they get what they deserve.
你说呢 擎天柱?
What's the play, Prime?
是时候找些援军来了
It's time for reinforcements.
去召唤骑士吧
Recognize one of your Knights.
唤醒你的同伴来接受骑士确认吧
快走
Come on.
好的 走吧! 快 我们走!
All right, come on! Come on, let's go!
大黄蜂 快走!
Bee, go!
快 动起来! 快走 行动!
Come on, we got to move! Let's go, move!
泰莎呢? 泰莎 快过来! 快
Where's Tessa? Tessa, get over here! Come on.
这边来!
Get over here!
跟在我身后! 我掩护你!
Stay behind me! I'm covering you!
如果我不掩护你了 那说明我死了
If I stop covering you, it means I'm dead.
但那不会发生的
But that ain't gonna happen.
吃我一枪!
Take that!
我是个邪恶的汽车人战士!
I'm a wicked warrior robot!
该死!
Goddamn!
快! 马上走!
Come on! We gotta move now!
走 走!
Go, go!
敌人从街上追来了!
We got hostiles coming down the street!
快走!
Go!
大黄蜂! 十二点方向! 火力掩护!
Bee! Twelve o'clock! Cover fire!
我们被包围了!
We're surrounded!
快 快 快!
Hustle, hustle, hustle!
小心火箭!
Rocket!
走 走 走!
Go, go, go!
趴下!
Get down!
这真是绝佳藏身之地啊
This is the perfect place to hide.
一个大玻璃箱! 谁也找不到我们! 真是...
A big glass box! Nobody will ever find us here! That's...
开什么玩笑
You've got to be kidding me.
传奇战士们 创造了我们的力量
Legendary warriors, the powers that created us
如今想消灭我们
now want us all extinguished.
我们必须团结起来 否则就只能永远沦为奴隶
We must join forces, or else forever be their slaves.
所以今天要么做战友...
So today you stand with us...
要么做敌人
or you stand against me.
这里交给擎天柱了
We'll let Prime figure this one out.
非常明智
Very wise.
我才不会留下来跟他们搅和呢
There's no friggin' way I'm staying down here with them.
没门 没门
No way. No way.
只有团结方可存活!
Only together can we survive!
让我来领导你们!
Let me lead you!
不好
No.
我以为会是辆大汽车
I was expecting a giant car.
来吧!
Come here!
我们在给你自由
We're giving you freedom.
保卫我的家人
You defend my family,
否则受死
or die.
汽车人
Autobots,
我们要证明自己的实力以及我们为何在此
we're going to prove who we are and why we're here!
你就是想为那个人死
You just want to die for the guy.
这就是领导 或者洗脑 或随便什么说辞
That's leadership. Or brainwashing, or something.
不 这是擎天柱
No. That's Optimus Prime.
汽车人 我们要一齐冲锋陷阵!
Autobots, we charge together!
现在 出发!
Now, roll out!
我们被围起来了! 四面都在攻击!
We're getting boxed in! We're getting flanked everywhere!
帮帮我!
Help me out here!
任何活物都格杀勿论!
Kill anything that moves!
快 凯德 开枪!
Come on, Cade, shoot!
尝尝我的厉害 小贱人!
Come and get some, you little bitch!
来了!
Incoming!
不敢相信我竟然把命交到你手里
I can't believe I'm putting my life in your hands.
给你 别客气 拿上枪
Here. Be my guest. Take the gun.
- 来啊 拿着  - 不 我不想要枪
- Go ahead, take it.  - No, I don't want the gun.
- 来嘛 让你做主  - 不 我不要拿枪
- Come on, you can lead.  - No, I don't want the gun.
那就老实呆着闭嘴!
Then stay under there and shut up!
好吧 你会玩枪 所以你留着吧
All right. You're good with the gun. So you keep it.
枪绝弹尽了
Running out of guns and ammo.
尝尝老子的厉害!
Come and get some!
你们都死定了!
You're all gonna die!
干得漂亮 宝贝!
Way to go, baby!
枪法不错 凯德!
Good shooting, Cade!
我像芭蕾舞女一样 旋转扒皮割喉咙!
I'm like a fat ballerina who takes scalps and slits throats!
抽中下下签了吧!
Got your fortune cookie!
去死吧 小废物
Come here, you little punk.
拉开火线! 我快顶不住了!
Pull the pin! I'm dying out here!
给! 拿着 拿着!
Here! Take it. Take it!
帮下忙! 帮下忙!
Little help! Little help!
点着了! 着了 着了 快拿走!
It's live! It's live, it's live. Take it!
你给我干嘛?
What do you want me to do with it?
- 扔出去啊!  - 给我 给我!
- Just throw it!  - Give, give, give!
坏消息 凯德
Got some bad news, Cade.
我没有子弹 也没有主意了
I'm out of ammo and out of ideas.
再快点! 快!
Faster! Go!
我要杀了你!
I'll kill you!
冲啊!
Charge!
不 不可能!
No, impossible!
他们把一切都毁了!
They're ruining everything!
吃我一拳!
Take that!
给我滚开
Get off me.
- 起来 探长!  - 我不行了
- Get up, Hound!  - I can't go on.
但你要继续战斗啊!
But you gotta keep fighting!
油箱空了 兄弟
Tank's empty, bro.
外面还有很多敌人 如果你不起来战斗
There's more of 'em coming. If you don't get up
我们会死的 快点!
and fight, we're going to die. Let's go!
进攻!
Attack!
擎天柱来了!
Optimus is here!
大黄蜂 跳起来!
Bee, jump!
我讨厌山寨货
I hate cheap knockoffs.
干得漂亮!
Awesome job!
- 你  - 谁?
- You.  - Who?
- 你  - 过来
- You.  - Step forward.
慢着 为什么?
Wait. Why?
你的科研要为人类灭绝负责任
Your science will be responsible for humanity's extinction.
好吧 我知道你对生命伦理这事很敏感
All right. I know that you're sensitive to this whole bioethical dilemma.
或许他只是想听你说
Maybe all he wants to hear you say is
有的东西根本不该发明出来
that some things should never be invented.
好吧
Okay.
我们带你离开这座城市
We'll lead you out of the city.
把种子安全送到山里
Get that Seed safely to the hills.
坐这辆车
Use this car.
他差点吃了我!
He almost ate me!
好的 能开!
All right, we're good!
好了 我们走!
All right, let's go!
给我从驾驶位上让开
Get out of that seat.
有我这样的儿子你很幸运
And you're one lucky dad to have me.
好吧 幸运小帅哥 没问题 你开车 我们走
Okay, Lucky Charms. You got that. You drive. Let's go.
你干嘛了?
What did you do?
我不知道 但肯定有问题
I don't know. I don't know, but it's an issue.
- 你按到按钮了吗?  - 会爆炸吗?
- Did you press a button?  - Is it gonna blow up?
不知道
I don't know.
你那东西开始响了 所以你肯定碰到什么了
Your thing is beeping now, so you must have hit something.
- 会爆炸吗?  - 我不知道!
- Is it gonna blow up?  - I don't know!
炸弹在响 肯定说明有问题 还用想吗?
A bomb starts beeping, that might signal a problem, you think?
我的意思是它是个稳步闪光信号灯
I'm just saying that it's a steady blinking light,
可能是在计时之类的
which could be a timer of some kind.
也可能在发送位置信号
Unless it's signaling location.
给谁?
To who?
他从那边来了
我们得向中央政府请求帮助!
We've got to call the Central Government for help!
我现在就打
走啊 快点
擎天柱
Optimus Prime.
来找我吧
Come to me.
我靠
中国 北京
部长...
紧急事件!
我是国防部长
中央政府一定会全力支援香港
战斗机已经起飞了
就是这座桥
There's the bridge.
退后! 退后!
Back it up! Back it up!
快 快 快! 倒车! 回去! 回去!
Go, go, go, go! Back up! Go back! Go back!
快! 闪开 我看不到了!
Move! Get out of the way. I can't see!
- 肖恩 开快点!  - 好 淡定
- Shane, drive faster!  - Okay, just calm down.
- 肖恩 小心!  - 哇 哇!
- Shane, watch out!  - Whoa, whoa, whoa!
- 躲起来!  - 倒车! 倒车!
- Get cover!  - Back up! Back! Back up!
汽车人 后退!
Autobots, fall back!
- 快 快走! 闪开!  - 闪开
- Come on, move! Out of my way!  - Get out of the way!
- 小心!  - 撞吧! 直接撞!
- Look out!  - Just hit them! Just hit them!
是块巨型磁铁!
It's a big magnet!
把金属吸起来然后扔下去!
It's sucking up metal and dropping it!
- 再快点! 快点!  - 快走!
- Go faster! Go faster!  - Move!
- 闪开!  - 来了! 来了!
- Get out of the way!  - It's coming! It's coming!
越来越近了!
It's coming closer!
快点 肖恩!
Go faster, Shane!
小心 小心!
Watch out, watch out!
- 小心!  - 当心!
- Watch out!  - Look out!
哇哦!
Whoa!
我去 我去!
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
不 现在它转头冲我们来了! 右转! 方向盘打死!
No, now it's circling back towards us! Hard right! Take a hard right!
快点! 闪开!
Move it! Get out of the way!
天啊!
My God!
不好 是磁铁 下车 下车
No. No, the magnet. Get out, get out!
快! 过来! 下车!
Come on! Come here! Get out!
不 不! 我们被吸起来了 拿好炸弹!
No, no, no! No, we're going up. Grab the bomb!
帮我拿着炸弹!
Help me grab the bomb!
我安全带解不开了!
I can't get the seat belt off!
拉我下去! 拽着我!
Pull me down! Catch me!
我飞起来了! 我飞起来了!
I'm going up! I'm going up!
抓住我! 抓住我!
Get me! Grab me!
拉我下去! 拉着我!
Pull me down! Pull me!
我解不开安全带!
I can't get the seat belt off!
I can't get the belt off!
我被卡住了! 卡住了!
I'm stuck! I'm stuck!
拿这炸弹! 我抓不住了!
Hold the bomb! I can't hold on!
拉开!
Pull!
天啊 我要被压扁了!
Guys, it's crushing me!
小心汽车!
Car!
快跑!
Move!
肖恩!
Shane!
- 肖恩!  - 我没事! 我没事
- Shane!  - I'm good! I'm good.
没事
I'm good.
大黄蜂!
Bumblebee!
嘿 各位!
Hey, you guys!
咦哈!
Yee-hah!
快
Come on.
找个安全的地方
Go find someplace safe.
我为你骄傲
I'm proud of you.
躲好!
Get cover!
凯德!
Cade!
汽车人 把炸弹带到桥那边 带离这个城市
Autobots, get this bomb over the bridge and out of the city!
爸爸!
Dad!
什么? 快走
What? Come on.
我抓住了! 我把炸弹弄走!
I got it! I'm getting this bomb out of here!
把枪给我
Give me the gun.
现在只剩你我了!
It's you and me now!
听着 擎天柱现在势单力薄
Look, Optimus is out there all alone.
什么? 你不能帮他
What? You can't help him.
我必须帮 泰莎 他是为我们回来的
I have to, Tess. He came back for us.
爸爸 别走 求你了
Dad, don't leave, please.
听着 我会找到你 与你们会合 好吗?
Look, I'll find you, I'll get there, okay?
爸爸 不 你会死的!
Dad, no, you'll die!
你要和肖恩在一起 你会没事的
You gotta stay with Shane. You're gonna be okay.
你答应我要保护她的安全
You promise me you're gonna keep her safe,
保护她一辈子 直到时间尽头! 答应我!
rest of her life, until the end of time! Promise me!
我保证
I promise you.
你是我创作的最棒的作品 泰莎
You're the best thing I ever made, Tess.
千万别忘记这点 一直都是你
All right, don't ever forget it, it was always you.
- 我爱你  - 别这样
- I love you.  - Please.
快上车
Get in the car, now.
爸爸!
Dad!
擎天柱!
Prime!
停车!
Stop the car!
- 你最好听话  - 不 你给我听着
- You better listen.  - No, you listen.
我不会离开我爸爸
I'm not leaving my dad.
好了 我们得坚持下去 然后封锁大桥!
All right, we're gonna hold the line, then block the bridge!
你看 真男人要有耐心
You see, it takes patience to make a man.
要耐心观察等待 默默地保护所有人
The patience to watch and wait, to protect all of us, quietly,
为了上帝与国家 完全不露痕迹
for God and country, without any recognition at all!
凯德!
Cade!
外星人没有好坏之分 伊格尔!
There are no good aliens! Or bad aliens, Yeager.
只是我们和他们
It's just us and them.
而你选择了他们
And you chose them.
永远都是
Anytime.
你不救自己反而救人类?
You saved the human instead of saving yourself?
你是我们的耻辱
You bring shame upon us all.
她从不听话 从来不听
She never listens. Never.
我给了你命令!
I gave you an order!
离开这里 马上!
Get out of here, now!
进来 进来
Get in. Get in.
嘿 嘿!
Hey, you! Hey!
凯德 离开这里! 这是我的战斗!
Cade, get out of here! This is my fight!
这是我的战斗 你们都得死!
It's my fight, and you're all gonna die!
快! 开车!
Go! Go!
快! 快!
Come on! Come on!
好! 什么狗屁机器人!
Yeah! Killer robot, my ass!
哇!
Whoo!
快
Come on.
所有人都闪开!
Get away, all of you!
快啊 泰莎 加油 泰莎
Come on, Tess. Come on, Tess. Come on, Tess.
开车!
Drive!
你看到了我 就不能让你活下去!
You see my face, your life is done!
快 快 快!
Come on, come on, come on!
好!
Yeah!
荣耀到最后一刻
Honor to the end.
你还庆幸能认识我吗?
You still happy we met?
当然
Always.
快!
Hurry!
快! 我启动了禁闭的炸弹!
Quickly! I'm setting off Lockdown's grenade!
抓紧!
Hold tight!
我们会再见的 擎天柱 因为我已重生
We shall meet again, Prime, for I am reborn.
偶尔做一下你的英雄也不错
Kind of nice being your hero for a change.
你一直都是 是我一生的英雄
You always were. All my life.
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
我们回家参加毕业典礼吧?
Let's go home to graduation?
好的
Yeah.
没事了 孩子
You're okay, kid.
过来 没事了 你是好样的
Come here, you're all right. You're all right.
我们没有家了 爸爸
We don't have a home, Dad.
家被炸掉了
It blew up.
这方面我或许能帮上忙
I might be able to help you with that.
勇敢的战士们...
Brave warriors...
你们自由了!
you are free!
我会一直与你并肩驰骋 三角龙!
I'll ride with you anytime, Spike!
你想我了吗?
Did you miss me?
没有
No.
这颗种子属于我们的创造者 不管他们是谁
This Seed belongs to our creators, whoever they are.
我依旧是他们的追捕对象
There remains a price on my head.
留下来的话会给你们带来危险
I endanger you all if I stay.
我要把它带到没人能找到的地方
I shall take it where it can never be found.
我们还能见到你吗?
Will we ever see you again?
凯德・伊格尔
Cade Yeager,
这我不知道
I do not know.
但当你仰望星空的时候
But whenever you look to the stars,
就把其中一颗
think of one of them
当成我的灵魂吧
as my soul.
保卫这家人 汽车人
Defend this family, Autobots,
就像他们保卫你们一样
as they have you.
无论如何
Defend
保卫他们
all they can be.
宇宙中有很多奥秘
There are mysteries to the universe
我们永远解释不了
we were never meant to solve.
但我们是谁 为何在此
But who we are and why we are here
不在其列
are not among them.
我们心中自有答案
Those answers we carry inside.
我是擎天柱
I am Optimus Prime.
这是给创造者的警告
And this message is to my creators.
不要碰地球一根汗毛
Leave planet Earth alone.
因为我现在
'Cause I'm coming
就来找你
for you.